PAUL: Yeah, hello everyone. Am I audible? Please do confirm in the chat.
PAUL: Alright guys, thanks for the confirmation, okay?
PAUL: Alright.
PAUL: So, today's discussion, it will be the continuation of the notebooks, okay? But, before that, just let's go through the main syllabus, okay, once, as few people have requested.
PAUL: Okay, so, like, what are the things that has been covered? Okay, and then we will continue our discussion. We'll be discussing the same notebook, like the vector store in the last class, as we have been doing.
PAUL: Okay, and then a little bit with respect to…
PAUL: Some new topics that we'll be talking about.
PAUL: And which are important.
PAUL: Alright.
PAUL: Alright, so I hope the,
PAUL: A syllabus PDF is visible to you.
PAUL: Please let me know.
PAUL: Everyone.
PAUL: Alright, so first of all.
PAUL: So, right now, very specifically, okay, so we have, gone through the first module, the foundations of RAG,
PAUL: Okay, and right now, very specifically, we have started with the framework line check. Okay, going forward, other frameworks probably, I think, from next week, we will be starting.
PAUL: data parsers. After data parsers, we will be starting with the other frameworks, like Lama Index and Haystack, very specifically. So, like, Module 1, majorly, most of the things are done right now.
PAUL: Then, in the next step, this is the LangChain module. So, with respect to the basics part, we have discussed nothing advanced, guys. The idea is nave RAG implementation. Okay, so till now, we will be always working with the nave version.
PAUL: Nothing advanced that we have discussed yet, any type of advanced implementation. Everything is just the neat version, the simple ones.
PAUL: And, right now.
PAUL: Very specifically, I have not started working with Hugging Face embeddings, if you look here very specifically. But, anybody has used all mini…
PAUL: Yes, LM, that particular
PAUL: embedding model. If you guys have not worked with, I know a few people have worked with, because very specifically, you people have tested it out. It's a free version. Other than that, right now.
PAUL: Majorly the things that I have discussed. Going forward, hugging Face embeddings also that I'll be taking as an example.
PAUL: Okay.
PAUL: He has 384 dimensions correct. It has also a 786 variant also, Saman.
PAUL: Okay? Alright.
PAUL: Now, the traditional RAG implementation, as you can see here, very specifically. Okay, so right now, so we have gone through the traditional RAG, like, basic similarity search, and even we discussed MMR. Okay, so maximal.
PAUL: Marginal relevance. Okay, so that part was in the advanced part. Later on, probably, I think, from Module 9, but little bit, we have gone through that. Okay? Now, with respect to building rack applications, this part also we have done.
PAUL: Okay? Now, this part, evaluation and testing. Okay, so right now, so this particular module that we'll be going through this week very specifically, because till now, we have not done any type of evaluation.
PAUL: Yes, we are just building simple tracks.
PAUL: So, this will be, like, this week's discussion. Like, I think, today only we'll be starting with the evaluation metrics of RAG. Okay, and very specifically, we'll be using Raha's phone now.
PAUL: Alright, so then, I think from next week, we will start with document passes. Okay, in your syllabus, I think in this particular brochure for evaluation, LLM as a judge has not been covered. Okay, it was not mentioned, I think, but I have taken that particular example also.
PAUL: Okay, so LLM as a judge, I felt that it is important. Okay, so that particular metrics, like, probably tomorrow. Okay, because once we have covered the mean REG valuation metrics, then we will jump into LLM as a judge, that particular concept also.
PAUL: Somebody's asking, please share this PDF in the sheet.
PAUL: everything is available. Always check Notion, guys, it's not like that…
PAUL: Okay, and even, I think, if you have before purchasing this particular course, you guys have gone through the curriculum, yes?
PAUL: Yes, I cannot say directly, but yes, roleplay is there, you are correct.
PAUL: Alright, so I hope everybody is clear, like, till now, so this will be, like, the Module 3 part we'll be completing, and then we'll be moving it with Module 4.
PAUL: Okay, so, right now, see guys, even with respect to LLM as a judge, right now, I won't be talking about, like, LLMs as jury, okay, like, taking multiple judges, okay, and then do a voting.
PAUL: that part I'll be keeping, probably, like, in the end of the course. Because whenever you are doing an evaluation, evaluation comes with a cost, okay? So, it means that the idea
PAUL: That you should try to use some type of local models, okay? It will be better, because multiple iteration, it happens with respect to testing.
PAUL: Okay, so I hope everybody is clear. So, like, this is basically the Module 3 part that we'll be completing, and from next week, we'll be starting with document passes. And in document passes next week, probably, like, doc links.
PAUL: unstructured, then I will come to Llama Pars, because Llama Pars is, I can say, the Llama Cloud service. Okay, it means that there are some limitations, because
PAUL: In the free trial, okay, I think you can do close to 100 requests, and vectorize is pretty much production. So, few proprietary stuff, and few open source stuff that we'll be talking about. So, this will be next week's agenda. So, at any point in time, if anybody asks, like, what will be the next week, it will be the document passes.
PAUL: And this week, it will be the, RAG evaluation metrics and the discussion, because in the last class.
PAUL: We discussed, but again, I feel that let's go through that contents once more.
PAUL: I hope the agenda is clear for everyone. Can we start the discussion?
PAUL: first project after Module 4, I feel that the first project event that you have, okay, so if I go to the first project, okay, so, like, even with this one.
PAUL: Because right now, building a basic CICD,
PAUL: Okay, so this stuff we can discuss. Okay, because right now, in this one.
PAUL: Yes. Okay, so probably the first project we'll be discussing
PAUL: after our Module 4, then. Okay, so probably next to next week.
PAUL: Okay, so that will be the first project that we'll be doing. Is this part clear? So, rough estimation, the second week of December, we will be discussing the first project, the basic UN Day system, with the complete CICD foundation.
PAUL: Alright.
PAUL: So I think we can continue.
PAUL: with today's discussion. Yes, everything will be in AWS.
PAUL: Alright, so… let's jump… okay.
PAUL: No more chats here.
PAUL: Okay, because I felt that few people are lagging sometimes, okay, with respect to implementations when I actually go through.
PAUL: Because, like, when I am coding… so, see, when I take multiple examples, I try to make it much more comprehensive at any point of time, okay? So, like, character-by-character coding is really not possible.
PAUL: Okay, because a few people, LLM acts as a judge, Gaurav Banerjee, alright, fine.
PAUL: Okay, who we'll be discussing. So, the idea is to go through sell by cell, and I always keep markdown with
PAUL: I can say multiple print statements.
PAUL: That's the idea, because going forward, like, after module, yeah, I can say probably 12 or 13, it will be lesser Jupyter notebooks, and it will be much more object-oriented programming. So the idea is, if you are not familiar with Python, please
PAUL: be good. If you are not good, you will be having problems probably after 1.5 months.
PAUL: Alright.
PAUL: So, let's start our discussion, let's open my anthravity, okay?
PAUL: Alright, so in the last class, so, little bit, so the same stuff. Two vectors, two that I felt about discussing. Okay, so one is quadrant, and the other one, one is VP8. So, which are widely used in production.
PAUL: Now, I think the font is visible for everyone.
PAUL: Okay? So in the last class, very specifically, with respect to the Docker setup, a few people told that, they didn't have… I hope that by this week, you have done the Docker setup in your system.
PAUL: Okay, because last week, that's why I totally skipped Viviate, but this time, the idea is that you showed up, so don't tell me that I don't have Docker.
PAUL: colleagues, so… Let's start with the same stuff, okay, the different types of memory. Okay, which?
PAUL: Quadrant provides. So right now, in this particular example, everything is with respect to OLAMA, as you can see here. Two important packages that needs to be installed in the last class, very specifically, I told the Lang Chain Quadrant, okay, and the Quadrant Client client.
PAUL: Okay, and similarly, for your other vector store, Langchain, Wuviate, and Wuviate client. Okay, so these two are pretty much important.
PAUL: Then for embeddings, in this particular notebook, as you can see here, Lang Chen, Ulama.
PAUL: That we will be using. Okay, other than that, I think everybody have, by default, the Langchen Core module in their system.
PAUL: Okay, and right now, the model that I'll be using is Novik Embed Text.
PAUL: Okay? And very specifically, if you want to run Viviate, okay, the particular image, because from Docker registry, you need to download the image.
PAUL: and you need to run it in your local system. For that, this is particularly the command that you need to execute, okay? So, when we will start with the Docker part, I will tell you the command once more.
PAUL: Alright, so first of all,
PAUL: Because this is a simple check with respect to field imports that I have kept it.
PAUL: Now, coming to the part, because this is completely practical, nothing with respect to the theory, the idea is that two vector stores you guys have already explored, which is the fires and the chroma. Now, we are jumping to, very specifically, to quadrant and Viviate. Okay, so total four vector stores.
PAUL: By this time, I think it should be familiar.
PAUL: The font is fine or not, please let me know.
PAUL: Okay, because, actually, like, This is 1920 resolution.
PAUL: Okay.
PAUL: Alright.
PAUL: So, the basic idea of embeddings you guys are already familiar with, so let's start directly with our…
PAUL: main part, okay? So, I will start the execution, okay, for right now. Let's check with the basic imports, okay?
PAUL: Now, with whenever we are working with, quadrant. Okay, now, very specifically, why I kept quadrant.
PAUL: I feel that, with respect to metadata filtering, Quadrant is much more powerful as compared to Chroma, because in the last week, we have gone through Chroma.
PAUL: Okay, so where directly you can initialize a filter. Okay, so for example, within the metadata, I am looking for a particular key value.
PAUL: Okay, so for example, the subject, and the subject can fill it. So, based on that, I can add filters. In Chroma, we have already done that, okay? So now, I feel that this particular metadata, because going forward, probably after Module 10 or 11, the idea is to prepare a rich metadata.
PAUL: So, there are multiple ways of creating metadata, probably, like, through LLMs also, it can be otherwise the manual process, okay, where you decide a particular, I can say, schema, and based on that schema, you always try to maintain.
PAUL: Okay, so let's start with the basics one. Right now, this is much more about the memory part of Quadrant, okay, and the metadata filtering.
PAUL: Alright, so let me start by taking the imports.
PAUL: Now, what happened to this one?
PAUL: Import error I got.
PAUL: Really, I have not changed anything in the environment, just wait.
PAUL: I think everybody knows this is the same notebook, just like the last time we were discussing.
PAUL: the lanction Core module?
PAUL: The real, like, I have changed nothing in this notebook.
PAUL: Yeah, it's available in GitHub if somebody's asking.
PAUL: Really, I haven't tested it yet, but let me see.
PAUL: Mmm, the… it's coming from Langchen, Ulama.
PAUL: Okay, let me check once, Ulama whether it's running in my system, I think.
PAUL: Okay, because I think Ulama was not running because of that, probably, I might get the error.
PAUL: And it's coming from this one, LangChain Olama, chat modules input chat olama. Alright, let me see now.
PAUL: I don't know why I'm getting this one. Just wait, let me open wrap, and let me check in the terminal once.
PAUL: Chat history with nothing we have discussed, so please, right now I'll be coming to that part.
PAUL: Don't worry. First of all, let me just check why this part is not working.
PAUL: Not clear.
PAUL: Because I have changed nothing in the last class based on this one.
PAUL: source.feelv slash activate, okay, and then comes here.
PAUL: Yes, I'm just checking very specifically.
PAUL: This is coming from 13, okay? So let me just do a pipe list.
PAUL: Because without this part, I cannot proceed ahead.
PAUL: Just wait, guys, okay, so let me just, make sure to fix the issue, okay? And then, probably, I will increase the phone. For now, I'm just fixing the issue.
PAUL: In my system, why it's coming.
PAUL: D.
PAUL: Really, because nothing that I have done it…
PAUL: Because there are no changes in the last class.
PAUL: -
PAUL: blank chain portrint formula that I have in my system.
PAUL: I know, for you, it might be working, because sometimes I create notebooks, so some packages I might change, because for Ragas, very specifically, like, I have installed some, other things also, okay?
PAUL: So that's why I'm thinking, just wait. Langshan Ulama embeddings, this is actually failing, okay?
PAUL: So, let me just check. Check this one, okay, and let me see, like, what is the main issue with this package.
PAUL: Great.
PAUL: Because Google MI is running in my local system, okay?
PAUL: So, one thing I will try to do, I will just try to uninstall the package of Olama, okay, and then…
PAUL: Okay, so, so, like, if I want to show you my debugging style, so generally, like, in this way, I try to do the debug, okay, because right now, this is the package which is creating the issue, as you saw, from Lancin Ulama import. Okay, now let me just try to remove the package from my system.
PAUL: Langchen Olama, okay?
PAUL: And I will just have it checked with respect to Langshano Ulama, the version PYPI.
PAUL: Chain. Mulong.
PAUL: What is the current version? Because, see, this is basically the latest version, which is 1.00. In my case, also, I can say it's 1.00.
PAUL: Hmm… Alright.
PAUL: Actually, Ulama, you don't need to run by default, it works. Now, why I got stuck here?
PAUL: Louis Bibb.
PAUL: And it's actually failing very specifically with respect to the OLAMA embeddings.
PAUL: So, just wait.
PAUL: Alright, because I feel the package is fine, there is no issues, but let me just uninstall,
PAUL: This package might create some issues, okay?
PAUL: So, lanchen hyphen ulama.
PAUL: Even I do get these type of issues, but the idea is to resolve these issues always. Then, in the next step, just let me open Python and see whether it works or not.
PAUL: Okay, now you can see this is working fine. Okay, so probably I don't know, probably with LangChain, I think, something that I might have updated. Alright, so it looks like this issue is fixed, so let me test it in the notebook now.
PAUL: Let me just restart.
PAUL: Okay.
PAUL: Alright.
PAUL: Okay, so right now, as you can see, okay, so I have increased the front, and I think the font should be visible to everyone. Okay, so you can see, right here, everything is working fine right now, after that.
PAUL: So, here, majorly, the imports that I have kept is, OS and SYS, pretty much standard Python modules. Then comes from Langshan code document, report document. So, right now, I'll be creating a Langshan document, and after that, like, probably I will be saving it in the quadrant vector database.
PAUL: Then, in the first example, Langchain underscore quadrant, import the Quadrant vector store. Then, I'm… this is the actual package, because this package comes from the Langchain community, and this package comes from directly from Quadrant.
PAUL: Okay? So, using the Quadrant client.
PAUL: We can make a connection.
PAUL: Then, in the next step, there are a few, particular classes that I have called, like, filters, field condition, match value. Now, this is very specifically for, meta tag filtering.
PAUL: Okay? Then, distance and vector parameters, like distance, right here, you can think about, the cosine distance. Based on that, we will try to find, like, what will be the retrieved context.
PAUL: Okay? And a few vector params are there. So, like, vector params?
PAUL: Yes, in the last class I told anybody remembers what is the purpose of using vector params.
PAUL: So, whenever you are creating a collection, okay, or an index, because within a vector DB, the idea is that you will be creating a collection within which you will be saving all the embeddings. So very specifically, like, collection or index and multiple vector databases, these are the common names.
PAUL: So, whenever you are defining the index, okay, so the idea is basically that you should provide the dimension.
PAUL: Okay, so before creating that, it's not like that, okay, you can change the, size at a later point.
PAUL: Okay, it is not possible. So, whenever we are initializing,
PAUL: index or a collection within a vector DB. Okay, so majorly all the vector DBs always tell you that, okay, please follow what type of distance you want to maintain for that particular collection, and as well as what will be the dimensional size. So, these two parameters are very, very important.
PAUL: So that's why all these imports comes into the picture. Is this part clear? Why I have taken this? These three things are for metadata filtering.
PAUL: Which, in the coming examples I will show. And then, finally, you have your distance. Distance, basically, that cosine distance calculation. And vector params are basically responsible, like, whenever you are creating an index or a collection within a vector DB, we need to define. Like, this index supports
PAUL: This emitting size, and this distance.
PAUL: Okay, so that's why I have taken this particular import here.
PAUL: please let me know, like, is this part… because this is very specific to quadrant, if you change it, okay, then again, like, it becomes a problem. Okay, like, for every, vector database, you actually need to go through the documentation, and based on that, you need to take care of.
PAUL: Okay, so two things. These three things are responsible for metadata filtering, this is for index creation, okay, and this is also very specifically for index creation.
PAUL: Alright, now, when I'll be using this import, things will be much more clear, okay? So, let me see, first of all.
PAUL: Okay, so everything is working fine, yes. So right now, simply, I'm importing Olama embeddings, and very specifically, I have taken Nomic embed text, okay? So, this particular model is available in my Ollama.
PAUL: Now, so this is the first set of documents, so directly, I'm not loading any type of external one, I'm directly creating one, okay, using the Langshan document class, okay? And right now, for every document, as you can see, there is a content and there is a metadata.
PAUL: Okay, so two things while creating the document. So, like, here, rag combines retrieval and generation. And similarly, metadata, topic, RAG that I have given. The idea is that to put filters. I told you, like, metadata filtering examples.
PAUL: That I need, okay, that I'll be showing. So, because of that, I have kept this particular metadata.
PAUL: Okay, the idea is, very specifically, it's not only that you will be always dependent on the retrieve context, rather than you can be dependent on your metadata also. I feel that sometimes using metadata directly, you can get an answer. So, that is also good stuff.
PAUL: So, similarly, 3 documents that I have created.
PAUL: Okay.
PAUL: And then in the next step, so, print, created 3 sample documents, and based on that, okay, I'm just printing for each of them, a simple for you.
PAUL: Okay? So I think till this part, for everyone, it should be clear, standard.
PAUL: things that we have done using LanChain.
PAUL: Nothing fancy?
PAUL: Alright.
PAUL: Now, in the next step.
PAUL: Okay, so, little bit. So first of all, like, different types of quadrant memory that we'll be talking about. Okay, so that's why,
PAUL: I think here… okay, so this is a simple example, okay, with respect to the things that you have already gone through. Like, this is a meta tag filtering in Chroma. In Chroma, directly, you can do it, okay? Like, you can create a filter. Topic, which is basically the key in the metadata, and rag is basically the value. And based on that, you can actually fetch.
PAUL: But in quadrant, the syntax will be something like this, okay, where you take these three things. Import filter. Now, on top of what you want to apply a filter. Like, there has to be some type of condition, which is basically this field condition. So first, you have to define a filter. Within that, the field condition, and then comes your match variant.
PAUL: Okay? So that's why, very specifically, I've kept it in this way.
PAUL: Okay, so now this is a syntax. I think everybody should be familiar by now, because going forward, we'll be using this particular syntax.
PAUL: Because this is a simple syntax that comes from Quadrant.
PAUL: Please let me know that is this part clear for everyone?
PAUL: from quadrant client models, three imports. First, you have to create a filter, because this small f is basically the object of the class filter, and then very specifically, I'm telling mask, it means that it should satisfy.
PAUL: the condition. Now, I have to define the condition, which is basically metadata.topic, okay? So right now, this is the particular metadata that I am looking for, and in that, I will be doing a magic.
PAUL: So, a pretty much strong condition that I have kept it here.
PAUL: Alright.
PAUL: Now, in the next step, so let's start with the memory part. Once we'll be doing with the memory, in the next part, we'll be talking about the metadata filter.
PAUL: So, the first one is the in-memory, which is directly in the RAM that we do save. Okay, and right now, if you look here, so this is basically the parameter that is responsible to save everything in your RAM. It means that once the runtime is done, everything is lost. Okay, so nothing's saved in disk.
PAUL: It just holds a portion of the memory in the rack.
PAUL: So, like, generally, we don't use this particular technique, but yes, Quadrant provides this particular option also.
PAUL: So right now, the idea is to create a collection. Within every vector database, you will be having a collection. In quadrant, it is called collection. In few other vector databases, it is referred to as index.
PAUL: So, right now, using this particular object, quadrant line memory, okay, I'm calling this particular function the recreateCollection, as you can see here, and I'm giving a name to that particular collection. My underscore collection underscore memory.
PAUL: Okay.
PAUL: Then comes to your vector config. I told you.
PAUL: for creating your vector database, or basically for creating your collection within the vector database, two important parameters are required. One is the dimension size, and the other one is the distance. So right now, I'm telling that, okay, the embedding model that I am using, which is Nomic embed text, okay?
PAUL: The size is?
PAUL: 768. Okay, and the distance for this particular vector dB, it will support distance lost cosine, okay, which is basically the cosine distance in simple terms.
PAUL: Is this part clear?
PAUL: Because this is a simple, command using which we'll be creating an index within a vector database.
PAUL: Okay?
PAUL: Now, with respect to the next part, okay? Now, can you explain again? Can you explain again? 4 people have told, can you explain again?
PAUL: Alright, let me just open my notes, because there is nothing to explain here. These are standard boilerplates.
PAUL: Okay, but let me just open the notes, okay?
PAUL: How many of you are comfortable with this particular? Because, really, this is a vector database, and there are more than 500 vector databases in the market.
PAUL: Why the size is fixed?
PAUL: It has to be fixed.
PAUL: You can't do, embedding comparisons at any point of time, okay? Just wait, let me just open my notes.
PAUL: really… Okay, so my notability…
PAUL: Just wait, okay? So, let's open the notes, and I will just try to make the major points here.
PAUL: I think this is the rack batch, okay? So, screen share advanced iPad Fire Cable, okay? Please let me know once you guys are able to see the, iPad charts.
PAUL: Okay.
PAUL: Understood.
PAUL: Perfect.
PAUL: Now, somebody's asking in chat what is Quadrant, really?
PAUL: Okay, so right now… Quadrant, Hello there?
PAUL: VectorDB.
PAUL: Okay.
PAUL: And Y quadrant, very specifically, Okay, so, like, the idea is to show metadata filtering.
PAUL: Now, here, right now, the first example is with respect to memory.
PAUL: Okay, so whenever you are creating a collection, so, like, inside a vector TV, Okay.
PAUL: You can have multiple collections.
PAUL: Okay, like Collection 1, Collection 2, Collection 3, Collection 4, Okay.
PAUL: inductment.
PAUL: Now, the first one which we have is basically the in-memory one.
PAUL: Okay, it means that nothing is stored in the disk, everything is saved pretty much in the RAM itself. It means that once the execution is done, okay, or basically available only in runtime.
PAUL: Okay.
PAUL: As simple as that, okay? Now, in the next step.
PAUL: So, right now, if we are creating an index, okay, so the idea is that whatever the information, so whenever I'll be creating that particular collection, that collection will be available within the memory, okay?
PAUL: Now, to create a collection, there are two important parameters.
PAUL: Okay, so first of all, the vector dimension.
PAUL: Okay, and the distance.
PAUL: Now, the vector dimension has to be fixed. So, in this particular condition, 786. Can you perform, cosine similarity search? So, for example, if I say that my vector 1 is 786, and my vector 2 is
PAUL: 1536. Just tell me, is it possible to do this?
PAUL: That's why we fixed the dementia.
PAUL: Okay.
PAUL: So, very specifically, that's the idea, okay? And very specifically, we fixed the distance also. Because later on, I'll be telling, like, when we'll be coming to advanced.
PAUL: quadrant implementations, you can actually take multiple distances also. So, we always tell that, okay, for this particular collection, we want this particular dimension, which is fixed, which cannot be changed.
PAUL: Okay, and the other one is the distance. So, for example, right now, here, very specifically, I am using cosine distance.
PAUL: Good?
PAUL: Is this part clear?
PAUL: Pretty much standard thing.
PAUL: Collection is stored in a folder, it's telling… I'm telling it in a memory, no disk.
PAUL: So, why you are asking that R, it is a zip?
PAUL: What are the other type of distance? Euclidean distance, Manhattan distance, Jacquardian distance, lot of distance out there, Mity.
PAUL: Okay, how can we do image vectorize using quadrant?
PAUL: Just, you have to change the embedding model, whoever is asking this. Okay, so I hope this part is clear, the core part.
PAUL: Perfect, let's move.
PAUL: Yes, Modasa, RADIUS is also in-memory storage. Alright.
PAUL: Now, let's get back to our notebook.
PAUL: So, let's start with our desktop 3S.
PAUL: Alright. So, now, based on this, the…
PAUL: Now, this particular boilerplate that we have discussed, let me know. Anything that you guys are not comfortable with. Because the same thing that we have defined, that we have discussed.
PAUL: Okay, in the next step, the quadrant vector store, so very specifically, I am telling the memory that I'll be using, which is basically the in-memory right now, the name of the collection that we have defined, and what type of embeddings that we'll be using. Okay, so once I have defined that, in the next step, I am adding the documents, which I have defined here.
PAUL: Those 3 documents. As simple as that.
PAUL: Please let me know.
PAUL: Okay, that this part is clear, at least for this first cell that we have.
PAUL: Okay, so I will just try to execute this one.
PAUL: Okay? And right now, it is available.
PAUL: Okay, so it means that, within the memory, I've just added those documents which I have created using Langchain, okay, and all the vector params that I can say. I've created the collection based on the parameters of dimension and distance.
PAUL: And then finally, I initialize the vector store with the memory, the embeddings.
PAUL: And things are done. Okay, so once the initialization is done, in the next step, you need to add the documents.
PAUL: That we have previously created. Okay, now let's move to the next part.
PAUL: So, the first part is basically the…
PAUL: Similarities such, the most basic one, okay, which is the cosine similarity.
PAUL: Okay.
PAUL: Now, as you can see here, so directly, the results, so see, on top of quadrant store memory, okay, now this is basically the object. So, here I have added the documents. Now, on top of this object, I have to do the search. So, right now, what is this?
PAUL: So, this is a simple retrieval technique, can I say? Yes or no?
PAUL: And right now, the top K results that I want, which is K is equal to 2.
PAUL: And right now, for doing the retrieval, I need some type of query, which is, tell me about RAT.
PAUL: Yes, it's just like LangChain, but directly we're doing it using Quadrant.
PAUL: If you remember, in line chain, you actually create a ret, like, retriever.
PAUL: Okay, for retrieving. But here, directly on top of the quadrant store memory object, you can actually initialize a similarity search.
PAUL: Is this part clear for everyone, these two lines?
PAUL: This is just the retriever part, using quadrant, and not using land chain that we have done.
PAUL: Okay, and right now, if you look actually, here, okay, so…
PAUL: everywhere, quadrant, quadrant, quadrant. Directly, we are doing it. Okay, but, this wrapper, the quadrant vectors 2, this comes from flagship.
PAUL: Alright. Now, in the next step, so based on this, I will be getting some result, okay? So, as you can see here, simple, and right now, k is equal to 2. Based on that, we'll be getting 2 results.
PAUL: Okay?
PAUL: So, simply, which will be having the, I can say the highest similarity, okay, based on that, we are getting the results, as simple as that.
PAUL: Okay.
PAUL: Now, in the next step, so right now, if you look here, doc.pageContent, so the actual content that we have, and then coming the metadata part. Okay, so where topic is equal to rag, difficulty is equal to intermediate, color, now see, these things have you initialized previously.
PAUL: Please, let me know.
PAUL: Because collection name and the, the underscore ID. So, very specifically, if you look into the document part.
PAUL: Okay, only two things were there.
PAUL: Okay, now, the other two things that comes…
PAUL: Which is the ID. ID refers to a particular embedding ID within a vector table. It means that for every embedding, an ID will be maintained.
PAUL: And what is the collection name? It means that where the embedding lies.
PAUL: So, that is basically within this particular collection you're embedding glass. So, that's why these two things are automatically created. And, by default in Quadrant, the default parameters which are generated from Quadrant are referred through underscore ID. Always there will be an underscore. It means that you have not created it, Quadrant has created it for you.
PAUL: All right.
PAUL: Okay, now let's move to the next part, which is, right now, the metadata filtering.
PAUL: So, generally, whenever I'm… we are doing filtering, so majorly three logics are used, okay? The AND, OR, and the NOT logic.
PAUL: Okay? So, the mass logic, all conditions must match
PAUL: Okay. Should, like, at least one condition must match the all logic, and finally, must not. No conditions should match the not logic directly. So, now, the idea is to use these type of filters. So, let's start with the, basic one. Okay, so the must one.
PAUL: Okay, so in this particular MOST one, okay, if you look here, so this is a metadata filter, and what is the key that I'm looking for? Metadata.topic. Okay, within that topic.
PAUL: Si.
PAUL: When I created the metadata.
PAUL: Okay, so this part, really, try to understand.
PAUL: Alright, now look.
PAUL: Topic is the key, and rack. Okay, so these two things are actually there. Okay, so I will just copy this line so that I don't need to scroll up again and again.
PAUL: Okay.
PAUL: And that is the same thing that I have defined it here.
PAUL: Okay, so… yes, okay? So, metadata is equal to topic, right? So, the first thing, metadata.topic, directly, I am accessing.
PAUL: Okay, so this is basically the key.
PAUL: And with that, the value that I have for it. Now, the question comes, why you are mentioning RAG? Because, very specifically, the topic is already selected. This can be a valid question. Now, the question comes, okay, at a later point.
PAUL: Okay, can you have something like this?
PAUL: Please let me know.
PAUL: Can you have something like this? Yes or no?
PAUL: The idea is that you can have multiple values.
PAUL: That's why I'm selecting a very specifically one.
PAUL: Because in our example, I have given one, but you have to think, at the end of the day, it's simple Python, and there can be a list. Within that list, there can be multiple elements, okay? So because of that, directly, I'm selecting what type of value, okay?
PAUL: So that's why.
PAUL: I will just give this part a hashed for now, yes.
PAUL: Okay, so now, based on this condition, simply I'm looking for… okay.
PAUL: Now, the same stuff, similarity such, which is the retriever part. So, first of all, the filter logic. On top of the filter logic, I'm applying the
PAUL: filter. So here, directly, during the retrieval part, using quadrant, I'm passing this filter, which I have created here. Okay, the quadrant underscore filter object, and based on that, like, I'll be getting the results.
PAUL: Okay, so right now, as you can see, here, a very specific topic.
PAUL: Okay, as we have passed that, okay, and based on that, we are getting.
PAUL: Is this part clear with respect to the filter?
PAUL: Please let me in.
PAUL: Because this is simple, there is nothing so much complex.
PAUL: Now, somebody is asking, So, should we have something like match values or change?
PAUL: Yes, you can have, there is no restrictions in that moment. Every chunk has a different ID, exactly correct, Sahil.
PAUL: How query is irrelevant? If it directly fetch, that's how.
PAUL: The query is relevant, it means that
PAUL: That will be taken into account. Your cosine distance is also taken, okay? But.
PAUL: the filter condition. It means that you get a better way of doing the filtration. It's not only that you are dependent on cosine.
PAUL: Similarly, rather than, you have one more filter, which actually helps you to get better results.
PAUL: The idea is getting better results, and not to be dependent only on the distance one.
PAUL: That's why I'm telling this metadata filtering. Because if you're… somehow the distance fails, based on metadata also, you have some amount of priority.
PAUL: Okay?
PAUL: Because when you are making a robust system, okay, if the distance fails, what you will do?
PAUL: The idea is use multiple conditional logics.
PAUL: Okay, you have to make this test 1 pass, test 2 pass, test 3 pass, and then finally your answer comes.
PAUL: Okay, so that's why I'm talking about metadata filtering, and it's very, very important.
PAUL: I have already shown you in previous classes, like in production, how we do maintain those filters. A long list of attributes.
PAUL: Okay? Perfect.
PAUL: Chroma, ChromaDB has the filtering, but I will say it's, weaker filters.
PAUL: Now, multiple, filter conditions. Okay, now the next example with an AND.
PAUL: So, pretty much the same stuff, and right now you can see here, okay, in must, I am passing two conditions, just like…
PAUL: the AND logic. It means that this should be satisfied, and this should be satisfied. And based on that, I'll be getting the result.
PAUL: Okay, so this is the next example. As simple as that.
PAUL: So, right now, if you look here very specifically, okay, filter, topic rat, tell me about RAG. Okay, now, based on the query, tell me about rag. So, directly, this particular got matched.
PAUL: And right now, if you look, topic is equal to rank, okay? Now, here, what are the things that I have passed? Okay, so I think…
PAUL: I am just looking into the other cell, yes.
PAUL: So, right now, multiple filters, example and logic, so this…
PAUL: And right now, based on this particular filter which I have created, okay.
PAUL: So, a simple filter, and now this multi-filter that I am passing. So, here I have defined it, the multi-filter, the two conditions. Okay, the value is RAG, and the value is intermediate. So, two conditions are there that needs.
PAUL: To be matched. Okay, so one is from topic rack, and difficulty is intermediate. So if you look here, into your documents.
PAUL: So, topic rank, difficulty, intermediate.
PAUL: Okay? And here, topic vector TV, we know that, okay, based on this filter, what?
PAUL: This should be your answer? Yes or no?
PAUL: Alright? Now, because, see, this is one filter directly we're getting.
PAUL: Okay, and now I'll be passing this, okay?
PAUL: this condition…
PAUL: Okay.
PAUL: Now, look into the query.
PAUL: What is the query that I have passed?
PAUL: Tell. Me. About RAC.
PAUL: But, if you have looked into the document part, Okay.
PAUL: So, what was the document? If I directly take this one just with…
PAUL: I think it will be better, rather than scrolling multiple times.
PAUL: Now, look here. So, it means that very specifically, I'm telling the retrieval, okay? So, like, tell me about, right? It means that right now, the context matters, because directly the context is getting matched in the vector DB.
PAUL: And if you look here.
PAUL: In the next part.
PAUL: always getting the right query is very hard, like Monmouth. It can… you cannot make the query dynamic, but rather than…
PAUL: It can be depart… for example, based on multiple collections, also, you can create multiple retrievers, okay? So it's not necessary.
PAUL: So now, based on this, we are directly fetching the value.
PAUL: Okay, so right now, based on that particular filter which I have defined, okay, the quadrant filter in the next step, okay, and based on that, we are getting the result. So, the idea is simply that, through metadata filtering, you can always actually look into your results.
PAUL: Okay, based on that query that we have, tell me about RAG, again, the filter that we have. Okay, and the filter search results, RAG combined, your retrieval and generation.
PAUL: Okay, so that's why. So here, every time I have shown the example with must, okay, but you can explore the other examples also, like showed, must, underscore not, okay, because then it will be a pretty much long examples only with vector D.
PAUL: The idea is to not, rather than look into vectorDB operations, but to explore more, okay? Now, can you guys explore from here by creating a simple? And you can try out these important things, which we have, the must, the should, and must not.
PAUL: So, somebody's telling why you are hard-coding.
PAUL: Now, this part can be dynamic. It means that that is a decision logic that you need to define.
PAUL: I cannot make this part always dynamic, so it means that you can create a condition where, very specifically, okay, so if this condition matches, based on that, you are getting the results. Without… if you don't use any type of filters, then also you'll be getting the result.
PAUL: Now, the idea is you can always check that, okay, if I'm getting the results with filter, is it better or without the filter? In that way, you can apply a decision logic based on the similarity score part.
PAUL: So, there are multiple ways how you are creating it, but dynamically, we cannot always do it.
PAUL: It can be based on the query also, that you can actually look for that, okay, so this guy has asked a question about a specific particular keyword. Okay, now, based on that, you can actually look for that, whether that keyword is available within your metadata or not.
PAUL: Now, those type of conditional logics that you can create.
PAUL: Because at the end of the day, you can do a simple fetch operation, and based on that, you can actually create your logic.
PAUL: Okay, the idea is that, see, here, they are giving you much more power. As simple as that, you don't need to be dependent only on one thing, which is the distance.
PAUL: That's why I'm talking about this.
PAUL: Please let me know, guys.
PAUL: The idea is that metadata
PAUL: filterings help you to one more step, and you don't need to be dependent on that. It means that from the query, can you get specific keywords
PAUL: Okay, now based on that keywords, can you actually have a search? If the metadata fails, it's fine.
PAUL: Okay, it's not necessary that every time it will be applicable for every query, okay? But at least I can say for 10-15% times, it can be applicable.
PAUL: So, that's why the idea is, okay, to use metadata, always.
PAUL: Now, somebody is asking how to make it dynamic, like the value is right. Simply, based on this query, you will be actually looking for that keyword, and later on, you will be actually looking into a particular, I can say. So, you will be giving keys that, okay, try to find within these keys, like, topic or something like that. And based on that, you can actually fetch it.
PAUL: Yes, metadata fields can be much more in real time.
PAUL: Okay, so that's why I'm telling you you have to build a robust metadata. Alright guys, so I hope that this part is clear, okay? Because really, like, the idea is not to explore quadrant. There are so many vector databases.
PAUL: Alright, so this is the most named system right now that we have discussed. Similarly, you have your, multiple filter conditions with the AND logic. Okay, so this part also, it means that both the conditions should be satisfied, okay? And based on that, we'll be getting the result.
PAUL: Now… In the next step… okay, so, the different type of memory that we have.
PAUL: All right, SKI keep asking questions, so the flow of chat is really high, so everybody that I can kind of ask me those questions.
PAUL: Alright, so guys, please let me know how many of you clear, or should I take more questions?
PAUL: At the end of the day.
PAUL: Because, really, the questions that are coming is something, like, people are asking much more about semantic filtering. Really, like, I've discussed nothing about those things.
PAUL: I'm just trying to show you simple filters within a vector database. It can be chroma, if you change it to Viviat, it will change. If you change it to Pinecone, it will change.
PAUL: And right now, really, with respect to the syntax, this is very specifically for one vector DB. If you change the vector DB, all the syntax and the logic, everything will change. But your core rag logic, filter logic, those things will be available.
PAUL: Okay.
PAUL: Because the idea I see, I… the idea was I thought about showing you metadata, though in the initial part it is not available in your syllabus.
PAUL: But I felt that it is important.
PAUL: Alright, okay, so let me just check, okay, and then I will proceed ahead.
PAUL: Now, in the next step…
PAUL: Once… okay, because this is another type of memory that we'll be discussing, the option 3, which is a persistent. I think everybody knows about persistence, because in ChromaDB, we create a persistent directory whenever we use to initialize a vector DB. The same thing happens here.
PAUL: Okay, it means that you select a path, so right now, as you can see here, so this is the folder, quadrant underscore data. Okay, and within this particular, folder, we'll be saving the information.
PAUL: Okay, so it means that here, I think, somewhere around quadrant will be created, okay, when I'll be executing this piece of code. Okay, so right now, I'm just selecting the path
PAUL: And if you look into Quadrant Client, and here I am passing the path. The idea is to create persistent memory. So, because of that, it means that if I'm creating the collection, it will be available within our local file system. Okay, and not only available, like, within the RAM. If you load it, then it will be available in the RAM.
PAUL: Okay, so very similar, we are creating the collection. Okay, so once the collection is created, in the next step.
PAUL: Client is equal to quadrant, and just like in the same way, we are creating the vector store wrapper, okay, and then we are adding the documents.
PAUL: Just like last time we have done. Then, on top of that, we are applying a similarity size, so there is nothing new here. It's just only one change that I have done, where I have just passed a path, and based on that, so this part is not in memory, okay? Rather than directly, I am saving it.
PAUL: Okay, now based on that, whatever the result that I am getting? Okay, so right now, it's not about the similarity such, because here, no filters, it's just about creating. Okay, and right now, you will see that this quadrant underscore data, that got created, and you can see the collection.
PAUL: Okay, so by default, like, Quadrant uses SQLite, based on that you are getting. And the name of the collection is My Collection Persistent. Okay, if you remember, My Collection Persistent is the name. Okay? As simple as that. So, this majorly that you can use most of the times. I don't prefer in-memory. Okay, I prefer this one.
PAUL: Much more.
PAUL: Okay, now, because most of the times, the idea is that if you have created the embedding, save it in a local place so that you can later load it up.
PAUL: And, most of the times, like, if we are working with cloud clusters, okay, then I prefer this part much more, which is option 3. This is the easiest one, I can say, with lesser amount of code also, just within one line, you can do everything.
PAUL: Okay? So right now, if you look here, the same thing that I have done, quadrant vector store, but from document. If you remember, in Langshan, everywhere, this from document that we have been using.
PAUL: Okay, this from documents. So, this is a common function that I can say which is available. So, using that, also, I can create. And whenever I'm creating this particular, document, so what are the things that needs to be passed? Documents, embeddings, path, and what will be the collection.
PAUL: So directly, I feel that this is the most easiest way of doing an initialization, rather than using this persistent storage, because here, at least, I feel that multiple times you have to do. And can you say, see, here, quadrant client comes, it means that you are using the quadrant package directly.
PAUL: But here, what you are using? Quadrant vector store from documents.
PAUL: So, like, this is directly using Langchain, which helps you. Okay, so this is the most easiest way of doing the initialization, if you're using Langchain, but it's not necessary that you are… you will be using LanChain every time. Probably, directly, you can use Quadrant also. Okay, so that is the purpose of showing this.
PAUL: And I will suggest, try to stick to option 3 if you're always using Lanschain. So this is the most easiest way of creating. This is also persistent storage.
PAUL: So, right now, if you look here, quadrant underscore easy, this is the folder where my embeddings will be saved, okay? And the name of the collection is rag underscore collection. So, similarly here, quadrant underscore easy, if you look here, okay, here, collection, name of the collection is rag underscore collection.
PAUL: and then storage.sqlift. Pretty much the same stuff that we are doing. One, using the quadrant, the other one using LangChain. That's the only difference here.
PAUL: Okay? With respect to this, is this part clear? Because persistent storage going forward, you will be using this.
PAUL: every vector database has a batch operation, okay? So there is no restriction in that.
PAUL: Alright, now…
PAUL: Now, guys, we have discussed the memory part, now let's focus on what type of search operations that you can do in, quadrant. Okay, the one was the similarity search.
PAUL: Now, I feel that sometimes you need to give a priority, or basically a threshold with respect to the score also, that you can give. Okay? So right now, as you can see here, this new function that comes, similarity search with score. Okay, the idea is basically to get score, and based on that, we can interpret it.
PAUL: Okay, so higher scores equal to more similar. Okay.
PAUL: cosine distance ranges from minus 1 to 1, 1 is equal to identical, we can say, 0 orthogonal, minus 1 totally opposite. Okay? So, now, this is simple. Now, you have to understand what is the relationship between cosine similarity and cosine distance?
PAUL: Can I say that they are pretty much inverse?
PAUL: Inversely proportional, Can I say this?
PAUL: Because, see, if the similarity is high, the distance will be U.
PAUL: Pretty much simple logic. There is nothing rocket science here. Yes?
PAUL: If the similarity is high, the distance will be low. There are two vectors. I can say if they are similar. Can I say that their distance will be lesser?
PAUL: Okay, so always remember, okay, so if sometimes somebody express, and I have seen in an interview, sometimes they might tell you with respect to similarity, but at the end of the day, most of the, I can say, frameworks
PAUL: that tell you the answer with respect to distance, not directly on top of the similarity score. So that's why, like, if somebody tells you a number, just be always sure that, okay.
PAUL: This is similarity score on distance.
PAUL: Okay, if it is distance, the idea is that it has to be lower. If it is similar, it has to be high. So, an inverse proportional condition is…
PAUL: Now, based on that, so directly on top of the vector store, I'm applying a similarity search with the scoring option, okay? And right now, based on that, I am just printing out the results. Okay, now you will see that you will be getting
PAUL: the scores also. So I feel that getting scores is much better at every point of time.
PAUL: Okay, in Langchain, a separate method is there, the same thing that we have previously discussed, okay? Now, you can see here, vector databases, the score that you are getting.
PAUL: Okay, alright, so 0.79, 0.48, okay, so initially, the one with the higher similarity, okay, this is, like, vector databases, so I can directly say that, okay.
PAUL: Now, here there are no filters. It means that directly I'm telling that, okay, show me the cosine similarity result, but with scores, as simple as that.
PAUL: It means that previously you were getting the results, but you didn't know the score, but this time you are actually looking into the score.
PAUL: Okay? And now, what happens? So, for example, when you actually look into the score, it means that you have that particular score parameter. Now, based on that, can you create your own threshold? That, okay, I want result only when the similarity is more than 0.6 or 0.5? Can you set your own threshold?
PAUL: Yes or no?
PAUL: That is the purpose.
PAUL: Okay, so it means that you can have your own decision logic, where you say that, okay, the score at least needs to be matched 0.5.
PAUL: Okay, it means that if you try to create a threshold like that, then these other two results will be directly neglected, and only this one will come into account.
PAUL: So that's why I feel that this is much more powerful. Okay, so it's not only the score, but you should always look into the score, similarity score. The idea is that if your similarity score is low, so for sure, the retrip context will be of lower quality.
PAUL: Okay, and it will hamper your rag at the end of the day.
PAUL: Okay.
PAUL: Yes, you can set the threshold, whoever is asking. Okay, that's a custom decision logic that can always be taken.
PAUL: Okay, so that is the purpose of showing you this particular part with respect to the score.
PAUL: Mayur is asking what happens if nothing vectors? Okay, then probably, if there is nothing that is retrieved, then done, then you will move to some other tool calling, web search, those type of tools. It happens.
PAUL: Alright, so this is the part with Quadrant. The main functionalities that I love about Quadrant, I have shown you, okay? Now we'll move to the next part, where we'll be talking about VBA. Please let me know that, is this part clear for everyone?
PAUL: Nitesh, can this score be used, in filters?
PAUL: directly in filters, I don't think, because,
PAUL: In filters, majorly with respect to its metadata, and right now, this is not metadata, the score that is coming, okay?
PAUL: Now, for that score, you can create your own custom function, and based on that, you can do it.
PAUL: No, is that quality or semantic meaning?
PAUL: Is that quality or semantic? Meaning, this is similarity scoring, Marthaj. It's neither quality, I can say it will of higher quality if the similarity is higher, or the distance is lower.
PAUL: Can we set the similarity threshold every time? Yes, you can always create your own, similarity threshold based on a decision log.
PAUL: Okay.
PAUL: Yes, Mantage, getting your questions, okay?
PAUL: Alright, we had topK also, it also takes core consideration. Okay, now, Rishi's asking a good question. If we have passed the top key, okay? Alright, you selected topK is equal to 4. So, by default, the top 4, which is having the highest similarity, that will be true.
PAUL: Now, out of that top 4, if you want to do some type of filter, I cannot say that all the top 4 will have similar scores. The scores will be different. So, on top of that, if you try to apply some type of threshold, I can say that I can get the better version, the top tools.
PAUL: Okay, so in that way, we try to make things much more filterable.
PAUL: Is this part clear? Aruna is asking, score is similarity or distance, so right now, it's based on similarity.
PAUL: Mayur, is it, is defining, K parameters a mandatory? Mayur, yes. Generally, it's mandatory. You'll… it's a hyperparameter, so yes, you need to, get it.
PAUL: Alright, with respect to coding errors, I will look into that later on, okay?
PAUL: Rabi Basai, what is vector database in?
PAUL: That is the query!
PAUL: Ravi Basal, the question that you were asking.
PAUL: Alright, I've taken a lot of questions from the chat, okay.
PAUL: SK, just try to pass your question once more, okay? Because as you have told, probably it might be missed due to the flow, but just try to copy-paste.
PAUL: Okay, because next part will be starting with Viv here, just be sure Docker is running in your system, so please start your Docker, and try to pull the image.
PAUL: Okay, the command already, I have shared it. Okay, in the chat, this is the command. So directly, once your docker is up and running, please try to execute this command. In the meantime, let me take…
PAUL: How will the choice of vector store done in real-time projects, really? Like, it depends upon a lot of them. Business, okay, and generally, the top tiles that we prefer, like, Zillis, okay, or, Quadrant, totally. That pricing matters, so based on pricing, okay, what is your budget based on that, we do it.
PAUL: It's a Mahajan.
PAUL: Okay. In market, the top famous ones that I can say are Zillis is there, Quadrant is there, Nuviate is there. Okay, so these are widely used in production.
PAUL: Now, to set your custom threshold, you have to create your own function, Lakshmi Kant.
PAUL: Oh, great.
PAUL: Amitel must, filter conditions receives, over-similarity, right?
PAUL: The first thing will be similarity always, then comes the next logic, Amit.
PAUL: Yes, it can.
PAUL: Don't paste your chapter 4 or 5 times, guys.
PAUL: Alright.
PAUL: Is it recommended to set the similarity threshold with every retrieval?
PAUL: It is not recommended, really Aryan. It's not recommended, but actually, for your own verification, because sometimes what might happen, if you actually set a threshold and just think about
PAUL: you passed 0.5, okay, and you got a result of 0.49 something like that. Okay, then it becomes a problem. So the idea is don't be very…
PAUL: strict on the threshold, okay? Try to be a little bit lenient also.
PAUL: Okay, it totally depends upon the use case. If your use case feels like that.
PAUL: It needs to be highly acute.
PAUL: Right, it means that in healthcare or in other places, it means that the answer is totally, it can be, like, somebody can be dead. Okay. Okay, now, based on that.
PAUL: you can set that, okay, in this particular healthcare use case, you should have higher, similarity. But in other general use cases, you can be a little bit lenient on top of the threshold that you were setting. So it totally depends upon business and use cases.
PAUL: Okay, Amit is asking, what is the benefit if it is first similarity and then filter?
PAUL: our condition. So…
PAUL: Retrieval will only be very slow, because applying on top of filters, what happens? Basically, you don't need to search everywhere on it. It's because the search becomes much more optimized.
PAUL: Okay, so wherever that particular metadata is applied, then only. So that's why making the search more efficient actually helps.
PAUL: Alright, Mayur, in scenarios where the triple size is limited to K is equal to Z, where strategies can be employed to minimize the risk of overlooking critical, especially when we have large set of documents.
PAUL: Limited to 10, what strategies can be employed to minimize the risk of overlooking critical?
PAUL: Later on, like, very specifically, when we'll be talking about the advanced concept, my re-ranking will come into the picture. R-ranking will help you to do that.
PAUL: Alright, so I will just stop. The ideas that you guys should be having,
PAUL: this VVH image, okay? I've taken a lot of questions.
PAUL: Now, simply, you can take this, okay, and what you can do, you can open your terminal, okay? And, like, if… let me just open up…
PAUL: In Utah.
PAUL: Okay, so, name Viviate… And directly attach to this, so simply let me run it.
PAUL: The client slash will be it is already used by the container. Okay, alright, I think the container is running in my case. Okay, because I think it… I do already have this. Okay, this container is actually running.
PAUL: Alright, fine. I will just start the container in that case.
PAUL: Alright, so the idea is you guys can directly pass this command. Automatically, it will download the image from the registry, and then it will be executing in your system. It means that the container will be started.
PAUL: Which is basically the Viviate container.
PAUL: If you are not able to install Docker, nothing that we can do, simply people who are facing issues with Docker, they can skip it.
PAUL: Okay, or you can use some type of service like Lightning and others.
PAUL: Alfred was asking, what is MH?
PAUL: Anything that is stored with respect to the Docker, it's an image.
PAUL: Anything that we are saving in a Docker registry is called an image.
PAUL: Can you please face the command? The command is available in the notebook, please have a look.
PAUL: Okay? Because if I paste it… okay, I can't… I… okay, interesting.
PAUL: Okay, I have paste it.
PAUL: Just directly in the notebook, just try to take it and execute it.
PAUL: Because right now.
PAUL: I have not taken a cloud cluster, probably from, like, next week, we will start looking with cloud clusters also. Probably, with Quadrant Cloud Cluster or Zelite, Zealous Cloud Cluster.
PAUL: But for now, this is a Docker. And majorly in production, you will be doing this. If you have an, your own setup, it means that everything you are using of your own infra. So generally, like, we always keep our vector DB, okay, through a microservice. That is the best thing.
PAUL: Okay? Now, I… please, if I say, if Docker is somehow facing an issue, okay, later on, I can look into that. But right now, I don't want to take installation questions.
PAUL: Please let me know for in how many of your system it is running, because directly I've given the command docker run. Okay, now this particular command which I've given, it means that, first, if the image is not available, VVHCR, it will pull the image, okay, after the pulling is done, then it will basically run in the system.
PAUL: Okay.
PAUL: Yes, you can install Ulama Image in your Docker, there won't be any problems.
PAUL: Boop.
PAUL: Yes.
PAUL: Rather than installing Olama in your system, you can always use olama Dockerh.
PAUL: Fold it.
PAUL: So, first of all, let me check the connection is there.
PAUL: Docker installation part, during the installation of the tools I have shown you. Directly, there is… if you have Windows, you can directly install Docker Desktop. Even for Mac, Docker Desktop is available. There are the other options, Rancher Desktop is there, Kulima is there.
PAUL: The idea is use anything, okay? The idea is Docker client should be there in your system.
PAUL: Okay, so that's why these things already, which is shown, I, showed in the first class.
PAUL: Alright, so now I will just start with the Vivi. See, the Viviart part, I have not kept it complex, so let's try to simply do it. The idea is that, at least, let's get started with Docker.
PAUL: Alright, so I hope that everybody is able to run. Okay, if somebody is having problems during the doubts, I'll be taking that.
PAUL: Now, similarly, see, Vivate uses WHEREFILTER. Okay, now here, the filtering syntax is a little bit different. So, every database has its own syntax. It means that there is not a common syntax for every vector TV. So, here, Vivate uses where filter with a different syntax than Quadrant.
PAUL: where you can path, like, path, operator, values, so in the operator part, it is equal to, okay, not equal to, so based on those. So, simple VectorDB operations.
PAUL: Then value test exactly what you are looking for, that particular value. Okay, like, the main key is difficulty. And what is the value? The intermediate.
PAUL: Okay, so based on this, we can actually create it. Very similar to Quadrant, but the syntax is different.
PAUL: Perfect. So, first of all.
PAUL: As you can see here now, how I'm connecting it to my, I can say my vector DB, which is running in a Docker container, okay? So right now, if you look into the Docker container, so you can see here ports.
PAUL: Okay, so here, localhost 50051. So this is the default port which is used by Viviate Vector Database. Okay, so that's why, very specifically, this localhost, okay, so I need to pass this particular parameters.
PAUL: Okay? And this, I can see here, the default port that comes with that gRPC port, which is basically 5001.
PAUL: So, two ports are there, actually, Viviate users, but, 8080, and on top of GRPC port.
PAUL: How many of you know about gRPC? Anybody have studied GRPC?
PAUL: Yes? Like, when you are creating a alternate of API, it's gRPC. Okay. Like, yes.
PAUL: If you have not said it, leave it, okay? Because right now, it's not so much important. I feel that it's much more about making a connection. Okay, so directly host port and gRPC port. Using this, you can actually make a connection.
PAUL: Okay, so those are simple API-based concepts. If you guys are not familiar, later on when we'll be talking about FastAPI. Okay, those things a little bit I can talk about.
PAUL: Alright, so right now, this is how you make a connection from your local machine to a Docker container. Okay, very similar to OLAMA. If you remember OLAMA,
PAUL: used to do a very, not exactly this thing, but yes, we can parl that local host. We can, based on that, the default port which is used by
PAUL: OLAMA in your system, okay? So let me see whether this is getting connected or not, first of all. Because if I get an error, it means that there is some type of issue.
PAUL: Okay, so yes, I can say… so, right now, the default port, 8080, that's getting picked up, connecting to the local VVA, you can see, connected to the local store. So, what is the post port and the gRPC port, which is 5001?
PAUL: And finally, creating the vector store, added documents, okay, because here, what I have done, if you look into the syntax, first of all.
PAUL: Step 1 is making the connection to the vector DB. For that, this is basically the syntax that we have.
PAUL: Now, in the next step, the idea is to initialize our VV8 vector store, okay? And here, I am telling that what I am using, this particular connection. So, I am passing this particular connection as a client. Then I am telling what will be the name of the index. If you remember.
PAUL: I told you, somewhere it is called index, somewhere it is called collection. In quadrant, it was called collection, here it is called index. At the end of the day, same stuff that you have.
PAUL: Okay? And, right here, the index name that I'm passing, which is basically my documents.
PAUL: And here, text underscores key is equal to text that I'm passing, which is basically a field name for the text document. Okay, so here, in Vv8, you have a little bit, I feel, that more functionality as compared to Quadrant, but yes, few things are available here, and few things. So I cannot really say Vv8 is better than Quadrant.
PAUL: Okay, based on few functionalities, you can always charge.
PAUL: No.
PAUL: And I'm passing what type of embeddings I'll be using, okay, which is basically the Ulama embeddings for now, the same Nomic text model that we'll be using.
PAUL: Now, in the next step.
PAUL: adding the documents, pretty much, we had stored.add documents, and we are passing all our sample documents which we have created in LanChain.
PAUL: Okay? Now, in the next step, once we have added the documents, we want to perform a search operation, or a retrieval operation right now. So, directly, Vivier store.similaritySearch, tell me about rack k. Now, this syntax is exactly like Quadrant.
PAUL: Okay, so there is no, I can say, add, a lot of difference. And right now, like, add underscore documents.
PAUL: All those three documents will be indexed. Once the indexing is done, then you are performing a retrieval operation. Tell me about, and done. Okay? And based on that, we are actually, first of all, printing all the results.
PAUL: Based on the final search. Now, the idea is to use a filter. Now, here, the filter definition, if you look.
PAUL: Can you see here that we have not created a separate filter object?
PAUL: Rather than directly within the search we have created and filled.
PAUL: Okay, and here you can see the conditions are pretty much same. Path, okay, path refers to the key.
PAUL: the value text refers to your actual key value. And finally, the condition. Previously, there was must, should, but yeah, directly, like, equal to or not equal to these parameters that you can pass in.
PAUL: Okay, and based on that, whatever the result that you will be getting, okay, it will be. So this is a simple filter logic. I can say that the syntax is a little bit different, but very close to quadrant.
PAUL: Is this part clear? Please let me know in the chat, because I feel that this part and this part is pretty much simple standard, but this part is something new, so let me know. Are you guys comfortable with this one?
PAUL: Where the filter logic has been defined.
PAUL: Because the syntax is different, it is not like quadrant.
PAUL: Path is the key. Value text is the value. Operator, previously, we were defining that, okay, now, it should be a must condition, should condition, so based on that, they are, like, equal to condition. It means that it has to match.
PAUL: Somebody's asking how to pass multiple key values. This is a list, pass!
PAUL: How many k-values you want to pass it.
PAUL: Alright.
PAUL: This is a simple list, so you can actually pass multiple values, there is. Is it possible to parse the regids in filter contestation?
PAUL: Regular C, yes, you can pass. You have to create your own function, and based on that, but the regats should be, like, applicable with your metadata. It's not like you can pass anything, okay? So, yes, you can do that.
PAUL: There is nothing specific about UVA. The idea is to explore more vector databases, that's why.
PAUL: Alright, now, this is the first filter condition. Once we have done the filter condition, now, in the next step, just like quadrant, you have this particular function also, so similarity search with score. And here, I'm looking into the top 3 results, and the idea is basically, okay, to do very similar functionality, like
PAUL: Quite right.
PAUL: Okay.
PAUL: So, based on this, okay, so if you look here.
PAUL: the output that I was getting, first of all, based on the query, I was actually, getting the output, tell me about RAP, and based on that directly. Now, can you see here, the result is different. In quadrant.
PAUL: two things got created automatically. Underscore IT and underscore collection name. But in Viviad, there is no such parameters in the metadata. It means that additionally, nothing got created.
PAUL: Okay.
PAUL: Now, in the next step… okay, so right now, yes, this says, got an unexpected wear filter, okay? Where filter error is coming.
PAUL: Aww.
PAUL: based on this, because this is actually a print statement, I feel that.
PAUL: Just wait.
PAUL: Okay.
PAUL: With respect to this particular metadata.
PAUL: See here that I have passed filtered result.
PAUL: Okay, and actually, what's the result that I am getting from here, okay? So, I can actually look into this one.
PAUL: There is no such thing, it's totally your choice. If somebody asks you, why Viviate, why not Quadrant? Both are good, you can use anything.
PAUL: I use Quadrant much more as compared to Viviat, if you ask me.
PAUL: Alright, so this is where the query and the filter is coming, search with metadata filter. Now, this piece of code is actually breaking, okay?
PAUL: So, what I can do… let me just check.
PAUL: Because a little bit I need to do editing, because this is a long cell that I have, okay?
PAUL: Because now, you can see here, this exception is rising here, print tape, the Viviate error that is coming.
PAUL: This is fine, Viviate error.
PAUL: Wear filter, the hybrid executor, okay.
PAUL: Alright, I have to check the import and the version again of this one.
PAUL: the version that I am using, is it, problematic or not, okay?
PAUL: So, land chain hyphen UV8. Okay, so this is the version.
PAUL: Okay?
PAUL: Which is 0.06, okay? Now let me look into… TYPI, LanChain…
PAUL: Vivian, what is the current version?
PAUL: Okay, this is the latest version with respect to Langchain Vv8, okay? And also, I will look into the other package, which is the quadrant one.
PAUL: Srithan Nala, it worked for you, I know that. It can work for you. In my system, it might be failing, it can happen.
PAUL: Langchain Viviate, which is the Viviate-client.
PAUL: Yes, I know in a few systems it is working, as few people are telling. But at least, let me look here. Yes, 4.18.1.
PAUL: Alright, based on 4.18.1, Viviate client is 4.18.1.
PAUL: All right, okay.
PAUL: Now, what I can do, see? Because I feel that…
PAUL: The package that is coming, okay, and very specifically, that is coming here from the Hybrid executor, okay, this…
PAUL: I don't know.
PAUL: Fire printer, yeah.
PAUL: And this argument, let me just check whether there has been any change in the recent version of Podel. I'm using the latest version, so yes, there can be.
PAUL: some type of a change. Otherwise, I can always downgrade it to a different version.
PAUL: Okay, actually, as I can see here, based on the actual Viviat, the idea is to do the downgrading, if you look here. Okay, from the actual community, use this Viviat client.
PAUL: and the LanChen version.
PAUL: Okay, so majorly, the operation or the recipe that has been provided.
PAUL: That's so… Oh, great.
PAUL: I have to do some changes in the code, then.
PAUL: Yes, I know a few people might not get an error, okay? It's system to system, it happens, actually.
PAUL: Yes, yes, just wait, I am even resolving the error, don't tell me error. Right now, I'm working on the error.
PAUL: Because this is Client V4 version, so I'm just looking into one sample example.
PAUL: Q… W.
PAUL: Because exactly what is the change that part I am looking into?
PAUL: I feel that, should I do a downgrade operation, or an upgrade operation? Because…
PAUL: The latest syntax that we have…
PAUL: Alright, somebody pasted a piece of code Mayur is telling, try this one, alright.
PAUL: Okay, this worked for me.
PAUL: Okay. Alright, I will try this one, okay? Just wait, don't type in the chat.
PAUL: I'm actually looking into the chat right now.
PAUL: This is a syntax issue for a few people, it might be coming, but, let me just see this.
PAUL: Okay, so this is a new filter class in V4 of Vivate, which has been created. Right now, we are using V3. Okay?
PAUL: All right.
PAUL: Syntax doesn't matter at the end of the day, okay?
PAUL: Alright.
PAUL: Let me just take the…
PAUL: Just sweet.
PAUL: Okay, yes, this part is working, okay. So, what I will do in the code, okay, so probably let me add it as a cell, and I will push it, okay?
PAUL: Excellent.
PAUL: Okay, it's just a few lines of code, okay.
PAUL: I'm just sharing it in the chat. Okay, so you guys can copy-paste it from the chat.
PAUL: Darren.
PAUL: Okay, a little bit change in the syntax from V3 to V4, this particular version, the VVet client, because my VVET client is supported to V4.1…
PAUL: 4, I think, much more. Okay, and this is, 4.180. So, with respect to version changes, a simple change. So, right now, what I will do directly, this particular filter, I will take it, okay, and, Ctrl-C…
PAUL: And here, with respect to this particular filter that we have done it, I will just update this piece of code.
PAUL: I have deleted this one.
PAUL: Alright, I think the indentation issues are there somewhere.
PAUL: Variate vector store similarities, or just it?
PAUL: I think few partisan.
PAUL: Close bracket, I have not done it, okay, just wait.
PAUL: Alright, I think now it is better, yes.
PAUL: Alright, I think this is the only change that is required.
PAUL: Ask ChatGPT this is a simple syntax when you look into Redfield. Done. Alright, fine. Okay, now see, if you look into the last sentence that we have used.
PAUL: Okay, it's, very, very similar. Okay, so first of all, the query that you are passing the results, okay, and right now in the filter, filter by property. Now, this is in version V.1.
PAUL: I can say, 18, the latest one, okay, my code was compatible with V.14. Okay, so two options, downgrade or upgrade the code, okay? As simple as that. Now, filter by property.
PAUL: Same thing, the first one is coming, difficulty. So what is difficulty? The same thing here, difficulty is the key. Then comes your match condition, okay, so equal to, intermediate. So right now, if you look here, very specifically, value has not been passed here, okay? So now.
PAUL: I feel that, okay. Somebody is asking, please paste in motion.
PAUL: Alright, I can paste it in Notion also, okay? I've shared it in chat, how many of you got the recent version of the code? Please let me know.
PAUL: In Notion, I am adding it, but at least Okay.
PAUL: In top, only I'm adding it, okay?
PAUL: slash food block.
PAUL: Okay, I have added it here, you can directly take it from there.
PAUL: Can't copy from chat. Okay, fine. I've added it in. Okay, just one line change that needs to be added, okay? Now, I will just try to execute this entire cell.
PAUL: Okay, so… let me just see whether it's working or not.
PAUL: Alright, now I can see that, everything is working fine.
PAUL: Okay.
PAUL: Yes, this part, alright, make sure the connection using connection, okay. This is a warning, not a problem.
PAUL: added documents to EV8 fine, tell me about the rack. So, yes, I'm getting the search results, then applying the metadata filter query, tell me about the databases.
PAUL: And the, difficulty, intermediate. Based on that, the filter vector databases enable semantic search. Okay, alright. Now, based on this particular filter, we are getting the result.
PAUL: Okay? Yes, the code is working fine. Please let me know everybody got the recent piece of code from Notion, so that I can start with the discussion. Please let me know.
PAUL: Ramad is telling, can you push the code? Yes, I can push the code, but once everything is executed.
PAUL: Please let me know everybody got the piece of code, it's just one line of code at the end of the day.
PAUL: Okay.
PAUL: Volunte.
PAUL: Somebody's saying, name error, Viviate Rahul per year, please check your Viviate version, okay?
PAUL: whoever is getting. Can you please share the link? Already? It's available in Notion, so I think you can get it.
PAUL: Try to restart your notebook, and then try to execute, if you are getting that error.
PAUL: Because the same initialization to the container, we have done it once again, okay, so probably because of that.
PAUL: Working for me, taken from Notion. Great, Srinath Raju.
PAUL: Armani Vagwantas, can you commit to the code? Please check Notion. Armani is just one line.
PAUL: Again, I'm pasting it.
PAUL: In the chat? Okay.
PAUL: You can directly get it from here also.
PAUL: Viviate underscore, please restart your kernel and try whoever is getting. I think, till now, only Rahul got there. Okay.
PAUL: Guys, everybody is ready, please let me know. Can we start the discussion?
PAUL: I will just restart my kernel.
PAUL: Okay? Once my kernel is restarted, now I will start the same execution right now. Okay?
PAUL: So, only one thing that I added, a very specific filter class has been added this time, okay, in the version, 4.18.1.
PAUL: And here, the same thing, see, Viviate Rexter store. So, the initial part is exactly the same. Only one change that we have done it, where we have applied the filter. So, this is basically the part with respect to the filter. Okay.
PAUL: Now, directly.
PAUL: Okay, now this is the part with respect to the, filter. Please, everybody focus. I'm going to discuss. If something is not working, later on I can look into that.
PAUL: Viviate store similarity search, tell me about the databases. K is equal to 2, and then comes the filters, okay? So, filter by property, this is something new which has been introduced in the latest version. So, directly, you are applying two filters. So, first.
PAUL: The key, in the next step, the value. Directly. Two things, key and value directly that you were passing.
PAUL: Okay, so previously, the syntax was different, this time the syntax has changed.
PAUL: Only one thing that has changed. Okay, and now let's look into the query. So, tell me about the databases, okay? So, based on that, I am telling that, okay, what is my filter that I have applied? Difficulty is equal to intermediate. And based on that, I'm getting the result.
PAUL: Okay?
PAUL: Now, in the next step.
PAUL: It is with respect to the score. Now, this part is exactly with respect to…
PAUL: I can say quadrant. It's just, if you look here, similarity underscore search with code, okay? Because directly this comes from Langchain, that's why the function is exactly the same, okay? And based on that, we are looking into the top 3 results, okay? And finally, we are, actually printing it.
PAUL: Now, see… okay, so I will just skip it till this part, okay, and let's try to analyze some of the results. So here, if you look, first of all, the connection is done, creating VBA rector store, okay?
PAUL: So, right now, added documents to Aviate, index my documents, and documents is equal to 3. Basic search, tell me about the rack, and based on that, I'm getting the top 2 results, because I passed K is equal to 2. This is the basic search component. Once the basic search is done, then we apply it.
PAUL: metadata filter. So, based on that metadata filter, okay, so we're very specifically, difficulty, intermediate, and topic is equal to RAG, okay? But if you look here, the result.
PAUL: That I have, because based on the query, tell me about the RAN. Okay, and the result that I am getting, vector databases, enable semantic search, and vector databases, enable semantic search.
PAUL: So, right now, is equal to the condition that we have passed is intermediate and intermediate. Can you see here?
PAUL: Okay, now, this is where it differs. So, very specifically, I was looking for that particular metadata. So, tell me about RAG.
PAUL: Now, tell me about rack is not available within this particular metadata, if you remember. So, based on that, it is overwriting that particular search logic, and it is actually moving to the metadata logic directly.
PAUL: Yeah.
PAUL: Everybody remembers what is our document, so based on that, we are getting this particular result, okay? And finally, with respect to scores, so 111. Okay, so directly vector databases with semantic search.
PAUL: Okay, so here, I was looking for top case equal to 3, and based on that, I'm getting the result. Okay? So, creating Wuviate from documents, so this is the other way around which you have created it.
PAUL: Okay, alright. Now, let's go for a 10 minutes break, okay, and let me take some questions from chat, whoever is, facing some issues.
PAUL: Okay, because of installation issues, we get it, but fine. Okay, so I will just start a 10-minute timer. In the meantime, people who have questions, they can raise their hand, okay? I will take few questions.
PAUL: So let me start the clock, just one second.
PAUL: I think a 10-minute timer is fine, or a 15 minutes timer is required, you guys can let me know.
PAUL: If you guys want to have your breakfast.
PAUL: Okay, a few people are telling, go for 15 minutes. Alright, fine, I will go for 15 minutes.
PAUL: Okay, I think, okay, so it is visible, do I have a 15-minute timer, or not?
PAUL: All right, okay, now let me start taking questions, okay?
PAUL: People just raise hand, okay, SK and others, okay, like, very specifically the questions I could not, like, entertain during the class, you people can let me.
PAUL: Okay, so let's start with, Armani, okay? Sk, you can let me know in the chat, because, see, I might, miss something, so very specifically, like, one by one.
PAUL: The idea is to take a 15-minute questionnaire, and then we will start our discussion back.
Armani, Bhagwan Das: So, I have a couple of questions, okay? One is, I mean, any specific reason that you used Paviate?
Armani, Bhagwan Das: That is question number one. And the second one is, I mean, the conditions that you specified in the quadrant, right?
Armani, Bhagwan Das: Are we going to use, AND and OR? Is there, like, a kind of SQL we have, what you can say, R clauses, IN clauses, and all are available? Okay, if I'm.
PAUL: No, no, no, not everything is available. Very few things are available you can think about as vector DB operations.
Armani, Bhagwan Das: Okay.
PAUL: See, that is… vector DB operations are different, like, it is very specific to your vector DB. It's just like, one can learn the basic one. But here, what happens in every vector database, you have a different syntax and format. Every vector database doesn't support, like, all operations.
PAUL: Those are very limited, I can say.
Armani, Bhagwan Das: Okay, and you created an index, right? So, index is like a, what you can say, one time we create index, or is it like a, in, relation to what…
PAUL: create multiple indexes. Index is just like a collection. In MongoDB, you can create multiple collections. Similarly here, you can create multiple indexes and multiple. So, for example, in a company, you have multiple documents, one for HR, keep an index for HR. You have finance, keep it for finance. You have developers, keep it for developers. In that way, we can differentiate talks.
Armani, Bhagwan Das: Okay, and can I search… last question, can I search only in a specific collection? Like, you have uploaded 3 documents. I want to search only 1 and 2. Is it possible, or it's not possible?
PAUL: You want to search in only one document.
Armani, Bhagwan Das: Here.
PAUL: No, that is not possible. You can search in an index.
PAUL: Because, generally, within an index, there will be lax of documents, so you cannot do that. You can do that by applying the metadata filter. So, if that is unique, then the number of searches will be limited, based on that filter. I hope you get it.
Armani, Bhagwan Das: Got you, no, got it. Okay, thanks a lot.
PAUL: Okay, escape?
Sk: Hi, this is Matish.
Sk: Finally, thank you. Can you hear me?
PAUL: Yeah, yeah, yeah, I can hear, please go ahead.
Sk: Finally, after… Four weeks, one month, you were able to take my…
PAUL: See, I can able to take, probably, like, even not waiting, the sessions go.
Sk: No, no. I raise my hand every week, but that's okay. This is the first time I got an opportunity. I sent a message during the chat as well. But, here are a few things. I understand there are some silly questions everybody asks. What is a list?
Sk: how do you… what is the square bracket, close bracket, dictionaries? I understand you're answering those questions.
Sk: depends on various levels of people joining this class. I would really appreciate, just from a overall perspective, if you can please
Sk: look at the recaps, as you have done this morning. I would appreciate just
Sk: telling me what is a recap at the beginning of the class, what was covered in previous classes, because every time we are coming back on Saturday and Sunday.
Sk: And then there is no… nothing in between. We are practicing as time allows during the week.
PAUL: In the last class, we were discussing this notebook only, if you remember, in the last.
Sk: I understand, but with a line chain framework, I understand that as well. Yes.
Sk: But it would be good to give a recap at the beginning of the class for a general purpose. Everybody would be able to understand, and what you're going to.
PAUL: The thing I am discussing, which I have discussed in the last class.
PAUL: Same notebook.
Sk: Correct. Same simple rag, everything.
Sk: but I understand that, but this is as a general principle. If you can also tell us along the process, as you mentioned, during the different weeks you went through the
Sk: syllabus, right? Where we are, that would really help. And one more request, which would be during the middle of the week, not necessarily Paul, you, or…
Sk: fresh or anyone, but if there is a lab assistant, at least for a couple of hours, to be able to…
PAUL: After January, I'll be taking extra classes. So, like, that will be from January, because I know…
Sk: I know that from your life, you might be very.
PAUL: No, no, no, I will only take it. See, I cannot…
PAUL: Because if I take a lab assistant, now the questions you people might ask, okay, it becomes a problem for him. He might be limited to few things.
PAUL: Okay, then again, somebody will ask a question with respect to certain experience. It becomes hard for that lab assistant, because I know if I hire an intern in even one year, it becomes a problem, rather than I will be taking all those, probably. I plan for that from January, probably, on…
PAUL: I have time slots on Tuesday and Thursday. So, yes, like, probably 2-hour sessions that I'll be taking.
Sk: Whatever works best for you. Just, I know this is at the beginning, and with the holidays, it could be changing. And the third one is, I wanted to ask if you could
Sk: Go the coursework, or the initial ones, with the…
Sk: free-based apps, such as if you're using, instead of using OpenAI, if you could use with Gemini, if you're looking with.
PAUL: No, see, that I'm… in this entire course, I'll be using Openia, now it's up to you.
Sk: No, I understand. There are… there are situations that I use, I use, different set of,
Sk: softwares from what you use, and this, from my work perspective, Perplexity is better, so I use… we have a subscription to Perplexity, and that's the reason.
PAUL: So, see, it's totally up to your choice. So, like, you cannot say that you use this one, like.
Sk: Right. I hope it's a personal choice at the end of the day. Start with the free option, and then, of course, then step two, you can take whatever you please. It may be…
Sk: OpenAI may…
PAUL: Three options already I have told you in the previous class. I have already shown Gemini, I've already shown… so the idea is that anything that you can use. So, why this question is coming?
Sk: Right.
Sk: Please, the coding should be starting with Gemini, that way it gives us more confidence and will be useful.
PAUL: I have already shared the subtaxi. Like, I always do my experiments with OpenAI, so my notebooks will be with OpenAI. Gemini, SEO, like, anybody can use Croc also.
PAUL: Okay, so it's something like, you can always change the embedding model and the LLM up to your choice in the right. The idea is you play plug your stuff, and you can do that.
Sk: And it is not working. That is the main reason I am going back and forth with you. I don't want to take too.
PAUL: Which is not working? You can tell me.
Sk: when I am, using some other tools, even with the local…
PAUL: I can, you can always share the code, okay? I've already told you you can share a collab instance with me, I can always look into that.
Sk: Okay, and the next one is, if you are able to show us, objective running.
Sk: of what… So, we are using a particular set of, even though…
Sk: notebook, you are running through the different set of codes. I understand it's not easy to run the codes, and most of the time, boilerplate stuff is available in GitHub and other places. We copy
Sk: And instead of just running that, if you can tell us the summary of why we are doing it.
PAUL: That really helps me.
Sk: Generally, right now, whenever there is a retriever object, I tell.
PAUL: directly. Now, if you want a written summary, I can add it in Markdown, like, below everything.
Sk: No need for return summary, but why… so, you had some question, or you had some issues during the class. If you can just…
Sk: walk through them loudly and explain us why there is a summary. It's better to understand if there is a trouble. I really appreciate if there is something.
PAUL: That is, like, really troubleshooting and debugging.
Sk: Yes, I can understand, see.
PAUL: In classes, in doubt classes, the same thing. People have asked so many times. I always see that, always look into the version the first step, check the Python imports, same stuff that I have done.
Sk: These are the stuff that I don't know how to do it, because our production stuff is all normally set up.
Sk: with a particular set of options. So, when you are going through this, if you can help us understand how you are doing it, problem solving is the best part of development. That will really help.
PAUL: Even I know that 70% of the time, I do debugging and troubleshooting.
Sk: burgers.
PAUL: of the time, we write code. I know that stuff, but I really, like, see, the one that I.
Sk: during the.
PAUL: So, to…
Sk: Okay.
PAUL: like, it happens, like, sometimes in Python, but I got your problem.
PAUL: Okay.
Sk: Yeah, it really helps us to.
PAUL: with the results.
Sk: as you are thinking, it develops that reasoning skill. And finally, if you can explain why we are doing this, a particular step from step, that really helps me.
PAUL: This is why I have already told, very specifically, like, with respect to metadata filtering or creating an object.
Sk: ship.
PAUL: the idea was, see, metadata filtering, though it was not included in your initial module, I thought about telling this because
PAUL: Just of the stuff, I feel that metadata is important. I understand, perhaps.
Sk: covered a lot more than what is in the prescribed syllabus also, I completely understand. And just…
Sk: I'll stop here, because I know there are other people waiting for the questions, and thank you for the opportunity. First time, I'm glad I'm able to speak and get some of these things out of the way.
Sk: And honestly, you said that.
PAUL: I always share my mail, okay, if you remember. Okay, please, like, I feel that your batches, like, this batch is pretty inactive with respect to mails. Only two mails I have received, I think. So, at least, the idea is be active and mail with me, because I see that…
Sk: the group.
PAUL: It means students are there. Sometimes I cannot take that out, or probably your schedule might be packed after the class, you might leave. The idea… that's my planning for that extra class from January.
Sk: Really?
PAUL: that a little bit more connection is required, because this is an advanced course. If somebody's fundamentals are not good.
Sk: I hear the questions from the class, like, people don't even know Python, or they can't even decipher what is going on, so I didn't want to bother.
PAUL: If you look into my chat, okay, then… Then you will understand accuracy.
Sk: People are asking silly questions and bothering on this stuff.
PAUL: It's not about, probably, their fundamentals are not correct, okay? Because of that, it happens. It's fine, okay?
Sk: Thank you.
PAUL: No, you should hold it.
PAUL: Let's move to our next participant, okay?
PAUL: email ID app at the red krishnak.in. I've shared in every class. I think by this time, you guys should be familiar.
PAUL: Okay, so let's go with Salman, Rahul Parihar, and I will take, for now, Nitesh. So, 3 people. Let's rise quickly, only 3 minutes will be up, yes.
Salman Habeeb: Hi, Paul, this is Salman. So, my two questions. So, let's start with this quadrant. So, this VectorDB has UI as well, like a traditional database system.
PAUL: Yes, it does anyway.
PAUL: It has an EUI. In the cloud. If you are actually going into the cloud cluster, which later on I'll be discussing. Yeah, no, no, not the paid. In the free version also, there is a 2GB limit. Okay, in that 2GB limit, actually.
Salman Habeeb: Oh, okay, great. So, free, we can have 2GB of a free cloud.
PAUL: Yes, yes, yes, yes, yes. Generally, in the free stuff, you don't have UI, but, limited free stuff, like, in the list also, there is an UI, so everywhere there will be an UI. You can't apply filter functions directly from the UI, like AND, OR, those type of conditions.
Salman Habeeb: And in that case, we don't need to create the vector DB folder here in our project structure.
PAUL: Yes, yes, yes, it will be in cloud most of the times. The idea is that right now, I'm showing you a persistence, because if you are hosting your own infra, then it will be somewhere provided.
Salman Habeeb: Okay, and from the system design perspective, let's say if I have a local vector DB. So, how do we design a system? Does it have to be in another server, database server, or everything remains in one server?
PAUL: create a very specific microservice only for Vector ID.
Salman Habeeb: Okay.
PAUL: Okay.
Salman Habeeb: So, it… it is in the same server.
PAUL: It is… yes, it can… yes, it will be in the same server only. Through Docker Compose, we can connect multiple services, so yes.
PAUL: Or if you want to host it in a… somewhere through API calls also, you can make it.
Salman Habeeb: Okay, that is… okay, because with time, this DB will… size of this DB will grow, and then, obviously, it needs a maintenance, and.
PAUL: Then, through API calls, you can always make it as a separate external service only.
Salman Habeeb: Okay, so as of now, in this demo, which you are showing is, we have everything where this notebook is running, everything is local, so that is okay.
PAUL: Correct, correct.
Salman Habeeb: But in the system design, it is better to have a separate server, and then have.
PAUL: That is SDLC. There is nothing AI-related to that.
Salman Habeeb: Okay, yeah.
PAUL: It's just like MongoDB. It can be a cloud-based, or you host your own Mongo somewhere.
PAUL: Similarly here, also the same thing.
Salman Habeeb: And in notebook, where you are loading the document, let's say sample document goes into database, that is my overall ingestion pipeline, right? I can call it my ingestion pipeline.
PAUL: Yes.
Salman Habeeb: Okay, and as long as my documents keep changing and new records keep coming in, I can build a job on top of it, and that keeps.
PAUL: Probably a cron job, you can keep it, like, every 12 hours, okay, or something like that, a batch operation is set, that every time this time, new operation, or whatever the new docs that comes, it will keep on index.
Salman Habeeb: And these things we are going to cover in the project, then, time, when we do it.
PAUL: that particular operation of uploading PDFs, so, like, I'll be taking that example, but cron jobs and other jobs, I am not going to show that.
Salman Habeeb: Okay, that is fine.
PAUL: Separate. Yeah.
PAUL: Alright, okay, so now 15 minutes are done, okay, now we will continue with our discussion.
PAUL: All right, Raul and Nitesh, probably, let's see. Okay, so, like, taking questions, I know it takes time, but I hope you get it.
PAUL: Alright, just wait. I'll be back in one minute, then I will start the discussion.
PAUL: Just guys, give me one minute.
PAUL: Alright, so…
PAUL: Let me start sharing my screen. Okay, desktop… I think this is 3, okay? Alright, now, with respect to…
PAUL: on that part.
PAUL: All right.
PAUL: Hmm, can you push the code? Raul, only one, thing that changed?
PAUL: I can push it, but I'll be doing, like, after this part.
PAUL: Pradhan, there is nothing in Drive, please check GitHub, GitHub, GitHub.
PAUL: Alright, now, first of all.
PAUL: As, this part with respect to metadata filters, we have discussed, okay, with respect to scores also, we have gone through. Okay, now, creating a VVX store with, alternate documents. Now, very specifically, okay, now, this part that we have kept it.
PAUL: Note.
PAUL: This is nothing. Can anybody tell me what is the difference?
PAUL: Last time and this time.
PAUL: Just check. Only one thing that is different.
PAUL: Index.
PAUL: index is different. It means that
PAUL: within your vector database, you are just creating another collection or index. That's the only stuff.
PAUL: There is no other thing, because the rest of the piece of code is exactly the same, there is no other change.
PAUL: Okay, and finally, like, once we have done the connection, finally, we'll be closing the connection. It's just like a database. In database, also, you do the same stuff. Yes or no?
PAUL: You start a connection, then you close the connection.
PAUL: The same thing, because right now, my VectorTV operations are done, so I'm simply doing a final cleanup, or right now, I'm losing the connection to that.
PAUL: Yes, you can add filters later on, on top of this particular index that you have.
PAUL: Okay, here, this piece of alternate, when I'm talking about alternative creating documents, it means that only the index name has been changed, rest of the piece of code. The idea was to show that you can create multiple indexes within a vector database. That's the only stuff here.
PAUL: Because the rest, everything is same. There is no other change.
PAUL: Yes, at every point of time, you can add filters, there is no restriction.
PAUL: Filter adding is with respect to retrieval technique. Filter adding is not with respect to creation of an index or a collection within the
PAUL: vector database.
PAUL: Okay? You apply filters on top of your retrieval mechanism, not on top of your vector creation.
PAUL: Can you consider index as a table? No.
PAUL: Arvind, is there a way to find what indexes are already? Yes, that you can always check, like, every vector database has a documentation, and there you can actually look into, like, or you can list all the collections. Okay, all those information can be done with respect to a very specific vector T.
PAUL: See, guys, this is not a VectorDB class. Okay, when we'll be having the VectorDB class? Because in VectorDB, a lot of things are there. Then I'll be talking you about that. Probably, I can take Quadrant for an example, and then we can proceed ahead.
PAUL: Okay.
PAUL: Alright, so this is the first…
PAUL: thing that we have done. Mudhasar, we had in-depth,
PAUL: name. Okay, that is fine, that is based on the older syntax. That is the only difference, okay? This is the newer syntax, I think, because at the end of the day, it's the same stuff, index underscore name. Okay, there is no other change in the code.
PAUL: Once the index is created, how is it to add additional metadata? Metadata comes with your chunk.
PAUL: Every chunk will have a metadata mingo.
PAUL: Okay, so I hope that this part is clear, and we can proceed ahead with our next step. Please let me…
PAUL: Okay.
PAUL: Alright, now quickly, see, right now, the example that I have taken it here, it's simply, as you can see here, Ulama Quadrant. So here, finally, like, I am using Quadrant for embeddings, Ulama embeddings, the model that I have passed.
PAUL: This is a test embedding, okay, and finally, query test. So, the idea is that if you want to look into exactly how the Nomic embeddings looks like, okay? So, this is a simple print statement, which will tell you. So, this is just a test.
PAUL: For now.
PAUL: Okay.
PAUL: So, each document was converted into 768 numbers, which is, by default, I think everybody should be familiar. Okay, now, creating a vector DV, okay? And the idea is that once, within that vector DV, you'll be creating your collection.
PAUL: So, I told you, option 3 in, quadrant that we have discussed, okay? This one, from documents, the easiest way, using Langchain.
PAUL: quadrant integration that we are doing this one. So, within a single line, so quadrant vector store, first of all, okay, this we have already imported in our imports from documents. I'm passing my sample documents, I'm passing my embeddings, I'm passing the path.
PAUL: and the collection name. So, this is the vector DB initialization, and within that, I'm telling that I need a collection where, very specifically, the name of the collection will be Ulama Collection. Okay, and this is the local path where I'll be saving it.
PAUL: What do you mean by real embeddings? Like, dummy embeddings can also be created. Okay, right now I'm using an official model, that's why I'm telling it real embeddings.
PAUL: Now, with respect to this, so finally, once we have added the document here very specifically, okay? So, once we have added the document, okay, so in the next step, I am performing a retrieval operation.
PAUL: Pretty much simple. Okay. And right now, I'm just printing all that
PAUL: metadata with the actual content. Okay, which I have in my sample underscore docs.
PAUL: bit.
PAUL: Ning, in the next step, so ULAMA integration, I feel that, this is the same part, okay, so just like last time we have done, there is no such difference. The idea was to use very specifically ULAMA because of that.
PAUL: Okay, and right now, yes, that is the same thing that we have at the end of the day.
PAUL: Because right now, I have not used any specific LLM, as you can see here, till the retrieval that we have kept it. So, this is a simple integration of Pulama.
PAUL: Okay, I think previously we have done the integration with Olama. There should not be any questions, okay? Please let me know that, can we proceed ahead? Because I don't think there is anything that is remaining in this particular notebook to discuss.
PAUL: Ulama itself is a vector store. Who is telling Ullama is a vector store?
PAUL: Shivajas.
PAUL: Really, man.
PAUL: By this time.
PAUL: Puvulama is just a provider, embedding model provider, and an LLM provider. That's the only stuff. Okay? So, just take one minute, because the next topic is very, very important that we are going to start, okay? Because it's going to be 12.15, probably the class will go till, I think, 12.20.
PAUL: Because we will start with the evaluation metrics.
PAUL: MS, earlier, what did we say? Earlier, also, I think we used OLAMA embeddings. You can create your dummy embeddings also, at any point of time. Okay, but really, it cannot be used somewhere.
PAUL: Okay, probably with respect to search, it might not work. That's why I kept it, like, real and dummy emitters.
PAUL: Docker, there is no issue. You can stop your Docker container, because we have done all our, things, like, you can stop it, and if it is working, you can quit a Docker desktop also. Totally up to you. Okay.
PAUL: If you have low RAM, then you can do it. Otherwise, really, like, closing the container, not really required.
PAUL: You can drop me an email, Mahmat.
PAUL: The idea is that, with respect to your assignments, always share me the GitHub link.
PAUL: how to use Olama if installed in Docker? Okay, that is a separate topic, Satish. Okay, if you want, I can share a resource with respect to that. There is no due date, the idea is that you guys do it.
PAUL: I'm having issues with Viette and doubts.
PAUL: Okay, guys, I think… can we start with the next discussion? Because for the next discussion now, I'll be pushing the code. So everybody, please look into GitHub. Okay, and finally, try to, get the piece of code.
PAUL: Alright, so I think, text representation…
PAUL: This is not what I was looking for, I was looking for simple direction…
PAUL: Okay, do not close, find vectors, close… Great. Alrighty.
PAUL: Everybody, please look into GitHub, I'm doing an ink push.
PAUL: Okay, and, even with respect to lengthen.
PAUL: I've done all of CTRL-S, okay?
PAUL: Alright, so, based on the new code, so if we go to, your GitHub repo, okay?
PAUL: So, with respect to your GitHub repo, simply, right now, I have added this one, 10. RAG Evaluation with RAGAS and RAG Evaluation with LLM judge. These two notebooks that I have added, please
PAUL: Okay, because we'll be discussing 10. I don't think today we can discuss RAG evaluation with LLM Church, but we'll start with Ragas today.
PAUL: Yes, I pushed a new notebook.
PAUL: Yeah, everybody, please check.
PAUL: Is it bad if I tell Gemini to do this rather than manually? Yes, you can tell Gemini. Through Gemini CLI, you can interact with GitHub.
PAUL: Motors.
PAUL: The GitHub link is available in Notion, P, Satish.
PAUL: Ang Shuxeng, okay? Please don't ask for links when it is available directly. Here, the GitHub repo link is there. Please open Notion, okay, and get it.
PAUL: Once you guys are ready with the notebook, the idea is simply you have to perform a GET pool operation.
PAUL: Okay.
PAUL: our people who are downloading it, I'm fine with downloading also. The idea is that it should be available in your local machine.
PAUL: Okay, and I will remove this,
PAUL: Little time, okay, I will keep it.
PAUL: don't use Google Drive. This is, I think, only one time.
PAUL: We have used it, but this is duplicated.
PAUL: Please, Sethis is asking, can you send the Notion link?
PAUL: Alright, time sharing the Notion link.
PAUL: MNS, did you remove any notebook?
PAUL: I don't think I have removed.
PAUL: Any notebook.
PAUL: Because, there was one notebook that was rectrable, so that is probably after
PAUL: One month it will come. I don't want to discuss anything advanced right now.
PAUL: One basic question, if you pull your code now, what about the folder? It shows that the files have changed, will it overwrite, or how does it work? What about the recent code changes that will be available in my repo? Based on that, it, will be changed. So, yes, if I change any file, if there…
PAUL: is in your system with the pull, the things that I have in my repo, only those things will be available.
PAUL: The last notebook for vector database is deleted.
PAUL: Somebody's telling this.
PAUL: Where it is deleted.
PAUL: I can see Vector Store's tutorial IPY and B.
PAUL: We really like cushion, please check, check, check, guys.
PAUL: Alright, so now a little bit of theory that we'll be discussing. Okay, the idea is that to, get the basics, okay, so let's start with the evaluation fundamentals, okay? Because interact, evaluation is important, so I will switch to my notes.
PAUL: And let's see, can we start with the practicals or not, okay? So… iPad via cable… I think that…
PAUL: Alright, let me just switch on the end.
PAUL: Okay, so right now it's not about practical, please focus on the theory part.
PAUL: Okay, so we will start with the, like, the evaluation metrics very specifically, guys, okay?
PAUL: And, really, like, I'm using one framework, there are so many frameworks in the market.
PAUL: Okay.
PAUL: And, even with respect to… in the notebook, I kept the observability tool also as OPEC, but OPEC integration, I won't be discussing now, okay, but after this part, okay? So, let's start our very, very important concept.
PAUL: Okay, so…
PAUL: RAG Evaluation.
PAUL: Okay.
PAUL: And right now, the metrics.
PAUL: Okay? So, right now, with respect to the metrics, before starting with the metrics, okay, so, some metrics you have to understand dependent on frameworks.
PAUL: Metrics are dependent.
PAUL: On… Frameworks, so exactly the name that I tell you, okay? Probably it might not be there.
PAUL: Okay, so probably, if I say faithfulness, okay, in some other places, it can be groundedness. Okay, so the name changes. You have to always understand, it depends upon the framework. So, our framework that we'll be using is R-A-G-A-S.
PAUL: Ragas.
PAUL: Okay? The full form of RAGAS is referred to as RAG, and then Assessment. EAS actually stands for Assessment, so I can say R-A-G,
PAUL: assessment.
PAUL: Okay, how many of you have used Vagas previously? Please let me know in the chat.
PAUL: Anyone?
PAUL: Okay? Nobody has used. So, any frameworks that you guys have used in production, you can give me an idea. I think, somebody has told last time they used Galileo. Yes? Anything others?
PAUL: Deep Eval, okay, Deep Eval, okay, basic PyTest features are there, deep eval. Okay, but for now, like, deep eval is also good, like, I feel Ragas and Deep Evel, they are pretty good.
PAUL: I'm using for legal document, alright, great. Basic precision.
PAUL: Langsmith Opic. Opic, alright, OPEC is an observability tool. With OPIC, you will be doing something, no?
PAUL: Okay, nothing for rap mode also. Alright, fine, okay, everybody. Okay, a few people have done it, great, okay. There are other frameworks also, so D people.
PAUL: Neda, so…
PAUL: DPL is also there, but right now, we won't be discussing this one, okay? Our go-to will be Raga. So, we'll start with Ragas.
PAUL: And then, probably in the phase of the course, probably one more framework that we can discuss, okay?
PAUL: True lens, alright, yes, true lens is also there. Okay, so right now, let's focus on our first framework, which is the most easiest one.
PAUL: Now, the main problem with evaluation thing.
PAUL: I feel that a lot of student talks about evaluation and how to do the evaluation. Okay.
PAUL: One of the major problems that I feel that
PAUL: You can proceed ahead with evaluation if you have a evaluation data set.
PAUL: Okay, and majorly, okay, I feel that this is missing from everybody's use case.
PAUL: And this needs to be created by yourself. It means that, based on your documents, you have to create this evaluation data set.
PAUL: So today, also, I'll be doing the same stuff. If you guys look into the notebook, I have created the document, I have created the value, okay, all this stuff. By myself. So, whenever you are doing evaluation, it means that you need an evaluation set.
PAUL: Now, in our Ragas, the first, okay, now I will start with the major ones that I'll be talking about, the metrics.
PAUL: The first metric is faithfulness.
PAUL: There we go.
PAUL: This is the first metric that… okay, and in simple terms, if you think about, what is faithfulness? Okay, faithful if I'm talking about.
PAUL: The idea is that, okay, generated answer, okay, stick to the facts from the retrieved context, okay?
PAUL: This is a simple one. Generated.
PAUL: content.
PAUL: Stick… To. The.
PAUL: Retrieved.
PAUL: Facts.
PAUL: Okay, retrieve facts or retrieve documents, same stuff that I want to.
PAUL: Okay.
PAUL: So, in simple terms, what I can say?
PAUL: Faithfulness checks. Okay, so as simple, I can say check.
PAUL: If… The… LLM is… Hallowe?
PAUL: Cinating. Can I say this one? Please let me know in the chat.
PAUL: At the end of the day, you know that LLMs can hallucinate.
PAUL: Okay, it means that, think about, you made a query, you got the correct retrip context.
PAUL: But the LLM is giving you something else.
PAUL: The idea is that this faithfulness, it means that you should be faithful to the source material, okay?
PAUL: Faithful, To your source material.
PAUL: So, in simple terms, if I take an example, okay, probably…
PAUL: Okay, something like, think about a journalist, okay, writing a news story, or something like that, okay. Now, that journalist went into a press conference, and from there, he or she took some notes, okay, based on that conference.
PAUL: Now, the idea is that if, somebody is using those nodes, okay, and, asking the LLM, probably, to create something, okay, now those nodes actually becomes, you can think about some type of, your documents.
PAUL: Okay, now the idea is that based on the query, so probably you might say that, please try to create based on this type of documents. Okay, the idea is that the generated news, okay, should be on top of those taken notes.
PAUL: of the journalist, which he or she has written during that particular press conference. It means that your claims, exactly.
PAUL: Okay, so that's why, exactly what is the original information that you have. On top of that, you are doing a verification.
PAUL: Okay.
PAUL: So, this…
PAUL: Okay, so that's why, for hallucination problems, I feel that, yes, this is one of the major ones. Okay, that every framework. Now, in some other framework, the name can be groundedness.
PAUL: Okay, so, like, groundness is called as… okay.
PAUL: But for now, as we are talking about Ragas, so this is pretty much your,
PAUL: Faithfulness and sometimes. Okay?
PAUL: Somebody's asking, what is hallucinating? How many of you know the meaning of hallucinating?
PAUL: It means that you ask something and the LLM is responding something wrong.
PAUL: Okay.
PAUL: Yes. Okay? Out of the world, okay, or basically something irrelevant. It means that you ask something, okay, and it is giving you something other than the answer. So, the context you were looking for, that context is actually lost in the response.
PAUL: Okay? So, for example, okay. So, if I, take a simple example.
PAUL: Okay, with respect to, I can say.
PAUL: So, let's take some examples also, I think it will be much better.
PAUL: Because, actually, with respect to examples, I feel the main problem is we have to write a lot of stuff.
PAUL: So, so let's take some type of user input, okay? So, probably an input I have taken.
PAUL: And in this particular input, I have asked the question, okay, like, when was the first Super Bowl? Okay?
PAUL: Okay, now this is a simple query you can think about and is a user input, okay? Now, if the response is coming.
PAUL: Okay, directly it can be date or something like this, okay, like, January 15th… okay, 1967.
PAUL: Okay.
PAUL: Now, this is the actual information you are looking for.
PAUL: But, other than that, if I'm talking about this is the actual content. Now, what LLM will be saying, if you're actually looking for how an LLM responds, LLM won't be giving you exactly the response in two words. I can say that your LLM will be giving a bigger response, like, something like this, the first…
PAUL: Okay, then comes your Super Bowl.
PAUL: Okay, then hosted in some date, this exactly date.
PAUL: Okay. Posted on, like, January 15th, 1967. Okay. In Los Angeles.
PAUL: Because LLM always gives you much more detail.
PAUL: Now, this is the actual answer if I'm looking for. Okay, so you have to think about this is the actual answer. Now, LLM always does an expansion. Okay, now this is what your LLM responds.
PAUL: Okay, and this is the actual response you were looking for.
PAUL: Okay? Now, I can say that, okay, now the question comes about retrieve. It means that it should have some type of sources. Okay, right now we are discussing RAG, so we'll be taking that, yes, there is some type of document.
PAUL: Okay.
PAUL: Now, probably, you will be having this retrieved.
PAUL: text, okay?
PAUL: Retrieve text or retrieve chunk, in simple terms, you can think about a chunk, okay? So, in the chunk, there can be information, something like this, okay? The first…
PAUL: Okay.
PAUL: And then, probably, I can say… American Football League, okay, national…
PAUL: Okay? NFL or AFL World Championship in that way.
PAUL: It will have… it means that your retrieve context has that particular information.
PAUL: Okay, championship. Then, on, you know, or was played on.
PAUL: Okay, I hope you get it, I don't need to write an entire sentence.
PAUL: 1967, okay? Now, this is the idea. It means that when I'm getting the response, I'll be looking at, okay, that am I getting all the information from the,
PAUL: I can say, doc…
PAUL: Red trip context. Okay, and probably, if you look into the LLM in LA is there, so I can say, probably, here, also, it will be there, in Los Angeles. Okay, so let me just directly write KLA for me.
PAUL: Okay, it means that the claim that you were doing is correct. It means that if you apply faithfulness, okay, it will always check that, okay.
PAUL: First of all, all the, I can say, information that is generated, okay? Then we will check that each claim. So, step by step, let's try to break it, okay? So, with respect to the claims.
PAUL: extract.
PAUL: All claims.
PAUL: Okay, claims means, right now, that is sentences in simple terms, okay, because whatever it's telling in the generated answer, that I am telling its claim. Claim why I'm telling? Because I, there can be a condition whether it can be a wrong. So I can say that, okay, the claim can be correct.
PAUL: can be wrong, so I'm taking that particular keyword as plain.
PAUL: Okay, from… generated.
PAUL: Answer.
PAUL: Now, in the second step, what will happen, once you have extracted all the claims, or basically you have looked into the entire content, or all the sentences, then we will check if each claim is supported by retrieveContext.
PAUL: Okay?
PAUL: It means that, first, the entire thing came, so you will be breaking that stuff, okay, then you will actually check, step by step. And finally, 3 comes your scoring mechanism.
PAUL: Okay, so the idea is that the final scoring mechanism happens.
PAUL: Okay? So a simple, formula is that, okay, to calculate this particular score.
PAUL: Okay, so first of all, you will be looking into the claims supported by context. It means that the claims which are actually coming from your retrieve context.
PAUL: Context means re-trip context, I hope everybody gets that. Okay, so…
PAUL: Very tribe context, let me just write.
PAUL: Okay, and divided by the total claims.
PAUL: Total claims means all the claims that were
PAUL: Claimed by the generated answer, okay, or that was the response of the algorithm.
PAUL: Okay, so… This is the simplest formula that you can think about.
PAUL: Okay, so right now…
PAUL: It happens in two steps. Okay, first of all, let's look what is getting generated. The idea is that the thing that got generated, let's do the validation from our retrieve context.
PAUL: Okay, and based on that, we'll be giving a response, okay? Now, if I'm talking about the claims right now, so if I try to do a simple calculation, let's try to do… okay, so let's take some claims, okay.
PAUL: Disk claims…
PAUL: Okay, the idea is to take some, score, okay? So, let's take some, for example, in the response, it's told that the first Super Bowl was in January 15, 1967. Okay? So, the first…
PAUL: Super Bowl, I'm just writing in short form, SB, Super Bowl, okay, was…
PAUL: In January, okay. So, what was the date? 15, 1967.
PAUL: Okay? Now, if I say that, can I say that this sentence is correct or supported?
PAUL: Because this is available in your retrieve context. If you remember, the retrieve context was there. Okay, so simply from your retrieve context, this part.
PAUL: Okay, so if you look there, okay, I can see the date is coming. So, yes, I know that the retrib context is correct.
PAUL: No?
PAUL: In the second case.
PAUL: Okay, so… now, the second claim can be, it was in LA.
PAUL: Okay, so something like this, it was in LA. I can say that this is also supported content.
PAUL: Okay, it means that, yes, we do have the retrieve context, as probably, here, I told it, okay, in LA comes into the picture.
PAUL: Now, finally, your third one. If I say that, it was a sunny day.
PAUL: Okay, so, Sunny?
PAUL: a day.
PAUL: Now, do you think that this is important?
PAUL: This is not supported. Because this part, I can say that, okay, this is not in context.
PAUL: Okay, or simply I can say it at the LLM.
PAUL: Is… Hallucinating.
PAUL: Okay, it means that you added something. Now, if I try to calculate the final score, okay, total, 2 are supported, divided by 3, so I will be getting somewhere around 0.67.
PAUL: So this will be my faithfulness goal.
PAUL: Okay, so generally what happens? The score… so, score interpretations, if I talk about, interpretations…
PAUL: Okay, so if I say 1, what is the meaning of 1 here?
PAUL: Can I say that? Perfect?
PAUL: It means that everything is good. It means that whatever the claim was there, it is backed by some type of retrip context, in simple terms.
PAUL: Okay? So it means perfect.
PAUL: So, this condition becomes… All claims?
PAUL: Okay, HAB?
PAUL: I can say, retripContext. Okay, so for now, retripContext, I'm just writing RSE. Okay, you hope you get it.
PAUL: If I say it is zero, then what is the meaning of this?
PAUL: Yes, if I say zero, then what is the meaning?
PAUL: The answer is completely made up by the LLM, can I say?
PAUL: Answer?
PAUL: made up.
PAUL: by LLM, whatever the LLM which has been used here.
PAUL: Okay? Somebody is asking, what is claiming?
PAUL: What is claim? You can think about claim as basically the, in the response, the generated response from the LLM. So there, what is the actual content that you have?
PAUL: Okay, which you can actually ask a question, and you can actually do a verification using the retrieve context.
PAUL: Okay, 100% hallucination also, you can say that, okay, the faithfulness is zero.
PAUL: No support at all, yes, correct.
PAUL: Ashwin is asking, but LLM weights and biases can have that correct info. So, right now, I'm not talking about with respect to parametric memory. So, generally, like, we are building racks knowing that this particular information won't be available in. The idea is that, for now, we'll be taking the example that
PAUL: We are, totally using that, parametric memory.
PAUL: Okay? I'm not taking the example of that. The idea is that
PAUL: You don't want any additional information from your LLM to be added.
PAUL: who will generate this claim? So generally, like, most of the times, this particular question… okay, so I'll be showing you an evaluation set. In that particular evaluation set, that will come.
PAUL: Okay, so generally, we create a setup questions, Motas, okay? Like, setup questions and answers, set up questions and answers, set up questions.
PAUL: So, based on that, it happens.
PAUL: Sahil is asking, how much percentage do we need to evaluate as good for evaluation? Generally, we try to take anything faithfulness more than 60 to 70%. I feel that it's good.
PAUL: Is there any base score or benchmark? There is no such base score or benchmark.
PAUL: it, changes on use case to use case. But I feel that at least your answer should have more than, like, 50 to 60%. Because few things from the LLM that can be added, I can agree with respect to English grammar and other stuff, but the core content should always match.
PAUL: Okay, I feel that at least 60%.
PAUL: Yes, ground truth, exactly, GT or ground truth, that will say it.
PAUL: How will you evaluate in production? Create your own test set. Based on that, you have to do it.
PAUL: Now, probably your test set might be irrelevant, so that's why with respect to time, okay, you have to keep creating on your new test set, because you will be always getting new user data. From that user data, you have to create your test set, always.
PAUL: Gotham is asking, does 1 mean the model is overfitting? There is no. Model is no overfitting here.
PAUL: Okay.
PAUL: Is there any industry standard we should follow? There is no such standards. There are frameworks that follows, but really, I feel that, faithfulness course should be at least
PAUL: 0 to… like, at least more than 0.6, then I feel your system is at least good. If you have a 0.7, I will say I can trust your system much more. If you have 0.5, 0.8, okay, more than 0.8. So I will say that it's a very good system.
PAUL: If it's 0.9, really, like, creating 99%.
PAUL: Accurate systems is hard. It means that you can take that error rate of 5-10% always happens.
PAUL: Okay?
PAUL: Yes, we have separate,
PAUL: I can say, metrics for your retriever output and the generated output. Rajesh, Babatik, who is asking.
PAUL: Probably career, you can do that. Responsible AI, I'm nothing talking about right now. It's your thing that you can edit. Right now, I'm talking about simple rag evaluation metrics.
PAUL: CNS is asking, so evaluator LLM have its own response, which…
PAUL: might know that the questions are totally made by the LLM, then the reg have its own data set, and then the LLM response validated by the RAC, so this is a claims…
PAUL: Skuru.
PAUL: Rather than when you get an entire generated answer, you try to break it into different sentences. Like, each sentence will have some context. So that is one claim. It means that whatever the… based on your query, what is the answer that is coming? It means that that answer is being claimed by the LN.
PAUL: The LLM is telling that this is correct, but actually it is correct or not. So, that claim is a correct claim or an incorrect one.
PAUL: Or there is a hallucination issue. That is the main thing we are looking into.
PAUL: CNS is asking, so… Alright, CNS, this question, I'll be taking you in the docs, okay? Should you use MMR? Digvijay, it's totally up to you, okay? That is a hyperparameter.
PAUL: MMR, I feel that it is good, but again, I always don't look for diversity. The idea is, relevance is much more. So, in most RAG solutions, okay, you use lesser diverse value and more relevance value.
PAUL: How is supported and not supported calculated? That is… that will be done by the framework.
PAUL: Okay, in the framework when you'll be doing Monmouth, okay, so, like, I'll be showing you that part. But this is actually how it is calculated, using an example, a simple example that I have shown.
PAUL: Okay, and right now, most of the evaluation you'll be looking into every time there will be an LLM call. It's not like that without an LLM you can do an evaluation.
PAUL: Okay? Every time an LLM call will be met to check and to actually do the validation.
PAUL: Okay,
PAUL: Alright, how is supported and unsupported its calculation? It totally, depends upon the generated answer by the LLM. So, probably, there can be claims of, like, 20, 30. It totally depends upon the context which is generated by the LLM.
PAUL: Mayur is asking, is it necessary to access the digital accuracy of PDF that is, different? Mayur, your question doesn't come into context. Raja, do you have, evaluation on each response?
PAUL: Yes, you can have that, okay? You can do that, but generally, like, after evaluating, like, see, after one evaluation, how you want to do the other evaluation? Through some other evaluation.
PAUL: Okay, Rajat, it means that once you have done the verification of one LLM, if you feel that this is not correct, now let's use another LLM for that. Okay, instantly, if you want to do it. That is the fastest way.
PAUL: Okay, so as right now, I'm writing. After the class, you'll be getting how to validate this claim section.
PAUL: Except source of truth, what we are, nothing you are. It always needs to be validated from the retrib context, which is the source of truth, Hari Kumar.
PAUL: So, we can filter out less than 5 score answers. Yes, you can do that filtration.
PAUL: No.
PAUL: Okay? We cannot fool the results, should be only from vector DBA, and LLM should not apply its own knowledge. That is the idea, PEG, that you were telling.
PAUL: You did?
PAUL: Prashant Desai, we keep temperature is equal to 0 to get deterministic answers. Now, the deterministic answer can be hallucinated also.
PAUL: Okay? Whoever it is, Kelly.
PAUL: Okay, prompt or query quality, it's not about… Huh.
PAUL: Prompt quality also matters, query quality, but Prashant, that is not very specific to… that is much more towards optimization.
PAUL: Okay, is it possible to filter out LLM hallucination in prompt?
PAUL: to a certain level, but again, not 200%. You can ask the LLM that if it is… if you don't know, you can simply say yes or no. But I feel that that is not a very robust technique.
PAUL: Can you show how faithfulness evaluation can be done using which framework? Yes, I will be showing you in the practicals directly. I'll be taking a test set, and I will be doing that.
PAUL: Anirot, does it happen in real time, or we will do it before the… you will be just calling. I'll be showing you in the practical decision. It'll just…
PAUL: four lines of code, done. Everything will be done by the LLM. A lot of LLM calls will be made, okay?
PAUL: What will happen if the LLM doesn't know about that I am asking, so it will totally depend.
PAUL: What will happen if the LLM doesn't know about what I am asking? So, it totally depends on the RAG dataset.
PAUL: If it doesn't know anything about the RAC dataset, probably in that case, you can make a tool calling, probably web search and external retrievers that you can add at CNS.
PAUL: Okay, Haniru, does evaluation happen real time, or we will do it before deployment? Before deployment, you have to do, not in real time.
PAUL: Okay, in real time, you can add a separate one, but these type of things actually need to be validated. So, for example, say, in production, what will happen?
PAUL: Okay? First, you initialized one level of evaluation, you deploy it. Then, once you have deployed, you will be actually looking. Like, I have looked into the system for 36 hours. The users have used it. I will actually look into that particular responses of that user query.
PAUL: answer, okay, so I will actually do a validation. Now, once I have that, I will create a new test set, then again, I can do a validation on top of that. Now, that becomes an incremental thing. With respect to time, you can always make your evaluation data set bigger and bigger.
PAUL: Alright, fine. Now, everything…
PAUL: Okay, now I will stop taking questions. Okay, let's move to our next part, okay? And please don't write in chat.
PAUL: Okay, I will disable the chat for now.
PAUL: Okay, now I will move to our next one.
PAUL: the first evaluation metric is done, then the next one that I feel is very, very important, okay? Now, okay, before discussing this, I… a little bit I will be talking about
PAUL: duh.
PAUL: I think that this model is also important, okay? So there is basically that, metrics, mental model that we basically set.
PAUL: Okay? So, what this model defines, okay? So, first of all, you will be having a user.
PAUL: Okay? That user will be asking some type of question.
PAUL: Now, that portion will go to whom? The retriever?
PAUL: Okay, so it will go to the retriever.
PAUL: Okay, now on retriever level, you need to apply some type of evaluation. So, for example, the other things that I'll be talking about. So.
PAUL: context, Precision.
PAUL: This is another evaluation metric, don't worry. The idea is to list out the major metrics that I'll be talking about.
PAUL: Then comes your context recall.
PAUL: Don't ask me what is this, what is this? I'll be talking about, but right now, I'm just showing you exactly where in the model it lies. Then once you have your, then comes, finally, your context entity call.
PAUL: Okay.
PAUL: Now, these three metrics are, done on top of retriever level. The idea is that at each level, you do it.
PAUL: Okay. Then, once the retriever is done, in the next step, I can say that you… we have the retrieved chunks for now.
PAUL: In simple terms, or your retrieve context.
PAUL: Okay? So, somewhere, okay, so now, once you have this particular information, what do you get? The generator part.
PAUL: So, this is where an LLM come into the picture.
PAUL: And finally… From here, you'll be getting the… a response.
PAUL: This is a simple flow that you have.
PAUL: Now, these three metrics that I have defined, like context precision, context recall, and context entity record, okay, these comes in retriever level. Okay, these things we are going to discuss. For now, the first one that we have discussed is basically the faithfulness. Okay, now, this particular faithfulness comes here.
PAUL: And even with respect to… noise… Sensitivity.
PAUL: So, there is another metric. The idea is that, ignoring the relevant, okay, info and adding some type of irrelevant, that is referred to as noise.
PAUL: Okay, so your final answer is how much noise, so that it will look for. I'll be talking about that, okay, for now, just focus here. So, once have you… once you have your final response.
PAUL: Okay, so there comes your another metric, which is… Answer?
PAUL: relevancy.
PAUL: Okay? So here it means that addresses the question or not.
PAUL: In simple terms, if I say that, okay, so whatever the query was asked, okay, whether it is
PAUL: Addressing the main question in simple terms.
PAUL: Okay, so that's why… so this particular thing that I have… so this is generally the rag, we call it.
PAUL: Okay, the RAG, metrics mental mode. So, at each step, there are metrics, okay? So, at retriever level, you have three metrics. At generator level, you have your final, two metrics, okay? Now, if you think about
PAUL: Okay, these are also, so, very specifically, if you think about this and this, okay, it's actually in generator level, if you think.
PAUL: Because, at the end of the day, to calculate faithfulness, you need the response, and even to calculate your sensitivity.
PAUL: Okay, but it means that without the response, you cannot calculate faithfulness, and without the response, you cannot calculate the noise sensitivity.
PAUL: Okay? So, really, if you think about, there are two levels, the retriever level and the generator level. In the retriever level, you have three metrics.
PAUL: And in the generator level, you have 3 metrics. Okay, so that's why I'm including the generator and the response into a single shot.
PAUL: Okay.
PAUL: So, this is the high-level RAG metrics mental model that we sent.
PAUL: Okay, so the first metric that we have discussed is faithfulness.
PAUL: Okay? It means that groundness in simple terms, or the actual ground truth you were looking for. Okay, so faithfulness refers to no hallucinations.
PAUL: Okay, and similarly, like, noise sensitivity refers to that, ignoring the irrelevant things. Okay, so let's start step by step, and we'll be discussing the others also. The next one that I feel that in every framework there is something called as
PAUL: answer relevancy or response relevancy. Now, this term can be changing. So right now, if you look here, I'm talking about this particular metric in generator level. Okay, so using this, you will be actually evaluating your answer.
PAUL: Okay, so now, with respect to this, please let me know any questions if you want to ask with respect to the rack metrics mental model.
PAUL: How wrong the answer is? It means that how much noise it is adding.
PAUL: Okay, which is out of the context from the retrieve chunks.
PAUL: Please share this doc link. Right now, I can share it, I think, but, really, I don't feel that.
PAUL: Okay, because create a link…
PAUL: Okay, again, I have to do a sign-up and other stuff. Later on, I'll be sharing the PDF directly, don't worry.
PAUL: Okay.
PAUL: All right.
PAUL: Okay, so the high level, it means that it's not only in a single level, retrieval level also, metrics are there, and generator level metrics are also there.
PAUL: Okay, if I try to do a Zoom, few things might be missing.
PAUL: Perfect.
PAUL: So, simply, now we are going to talk about this sex.
PAUL: I can say these 6 metrics in RAMS. Now, it is not necessary that in every framework you will have these 6.
PAUL: Something, probably in some other places, there can be only 4, there can be only 5, there can be only 3. Okay, the major ones that I feel that, out of this, the most important one. Okay, I will just, tell you.
PAUL: I feel that these are much more important as compared to others.
PAUL: Yes. So, the first one is faithfulness.
PAUL: Then you have… Answer relevance, these two are very, very important.
PAUL: Then, these two. Context, precision and context clicker.
PAUL: These two are more important, okay, because, again, in every framework, you won't be having a context entity recall, which is very specific to RAGAS.
PAUL: Then even with respect to noise sensitivity, I don't feel that in every framework it has.
PAUL: Okay? So majorly, the major four ones, which is, faithfulness, also called as groundness, then, you have your answer relevancy. In other places, it is called response relevancy. Okay, so that's why that name keeps on changing.
PAUL: In some places, like, context precision can be only precision, or it can be only recall. So, in that way, things changes.
PAUL: Alright, I hope the mental model is clear. Okay, I heard that the LLM response is validated by
PAUL: RAG, and then delivered to the user.
PAUL: the LLM response is validated by the rack. How the RAC will do the validation?
PAUL: Ask me this question in doubt, okay?
PAUL: You can add external retrieval, that is different. Right now, this is the core rag, I'm not talking about you are having any type of external web call or anything.
PAUL: Yep.
PAUL: Right now, I'm not… Priya is asking, context entity recall means, have I told you anything about that metric? I told you that these are the metrics.
PAUL: I'm going to discuss these metrics one by one.
PAUL: All right, the idea was to discuss the high-level model. Now, this model changes. Okay, you can think about in some places it can be only 5 metrics, okay, or somewhere you might see two additional more metrics, which has been added by taking 2 metrics. Okay, there are certain, okay, it means that that
PAUL: How many of you know F1 is good?
PAUL: In machine learning.
PAUL: to calculate F1 score, what are the things that are needed?
PAUL: Those things come from other metrics, yes or no?
PAUL: That's the idea. It means that using two metrics, you can create some other metrics, okay? Now, a few frameworks have done it, but right now, I'm going to focus on the major one.
PAUL: Alright, so let's proceed ahead with our next, major, part, which is the answer relevancy. I feel that in every framework, it is there, okay, answer relevancy or response relevancy that we have.
PAUL: You're so… Also, like, in simple terms, response relevancy can also be the other term.
PAUL: Okay, now here, what it actually measures in simple terms. Okay, is the answer actually answering the question asked?
PAUL: Okay, it does not care if the answer is correct, okay, just whether it's relevant, if in simple terms. So…
PAUL: Addresses.
PAUL: Weather.
PAUL: Okay.
PAUL: the answer, answer or the generated response? The answer is now the response. Okay.
PAUL: actually… answering… the question.
PAUL: Okay.
PAUL: Simple terms, it will look for that.
PAUL: Now, see, when I'm telling that, okay, addresses whether the answer, actually answering the question, it means that
PAUL: There can be a scenario where there is only a part of the answer, and with that answer, there can be something else.
PAUL: Okay, so a simple example. So, let's try to understand, because using examples, it will be better. So, if I ask you in simple, like, what is the capital of France?
PAUL: Okay, and… If, in the answer, something like that comes, like, yes, the filter is beautiful.
PAUL: So, do you think that your answer is correct?
PAUL: Okay, so do you want me to write it? So, like…
PAUL: Word.
PAUL: Is the… Capital… Oh.
PAUL: France.
PAUL: Okay.
PAUL: And the answer that came… okay, so simply… Duh.
PAUL: a full tar.
PAUL: is beautiful.
PAUL: Yes. So, do you think that this answer is factually correct?
PAUL: Okay, somebody told Aniroth, like, along with Paris, if it comes, then it's okay.
PAUL: Okay, this look like a subjective metric, yes, most of the metrics are subjective only.
PAUL: Okay? Yes, this is just an opinion. So, simply, I can say that, okay, yes, that the answer might be factually true, but, like, totally relevant.
PAUL: Okay, like, here I can say that sometimes, like, totally…
PAUL: Irrelevant, okay? But… factually, partially true.
PAUL: Because we know that if it is added with Paris, okay, then it's pretty much correct. Okay?
PAUL: So that's why. It means that some part can be true, and some part can be false. It means that it's a mixture.
PAUL: Okay, so in simple terms, so that's why I've taken this example. It means that you won't get the full context, but maybe it can be a very partial context, but it is totally irrelevant. It means that, okay, something it might have brought, but really, that is not the answer that I am looking for.
PAUL: Okay, so the idea is that it will always try to look, because this can be one type of response. Similarly, if I say that the response is.
PAUL: Paris?
PAUL: Is, beautiful city. Okay, now this is R1, and this is R2. Now tell me, Is this correct?
PAUL: Yes?
PAUL: Yes or no? Please let me know.
PAUL: Okay, the question was, Q1, okay, what is the capital of France? And I'm telling you, Paris is a beautiful city.
PAUL: Okay, now it means that, see, this is factually correct. Means, I know that, yes, the capital that I have… okay, so this is very specific. Yes, I can actually look into the keyword.
PAUL: But the core information that I'm looking for.
PAUL: Okay, somebody's telling you it's irrelevant, huh?
PAUL: This is not irrelevant, guys. I hope the actual answer lies, but with that, there is some amount of irrelevancy. It means mixed.
PAUL: Okay, it means that you have some type of irrelevant info. So generally, like, if I say that, okay, so this amount of information that I have… okay, so Paris is the correct answer, but if I talk with respect to this.
PAUL: So this can be, like, I feel that, some type of irrelevant thing that came, okay? So, simply, I can refer to this as noise.
PAUL: Because really, I was not looking that whether Paris was a beautiful city or not. I was looking for what was the capital of Rome, so partially true. So, generally, this happens with the response of the elements. It means that part of your answer will be correct, and some part of the answer might be wrong.
PAUL: Okay, wrong means it will bring irrelevant context, and this is a very common problem that we do face. Okay, it means that partial relevancy, partial irrelevancy.
PAUL: Okay, so that's why. Both the things, 50-50 can be there, or 2080, so I hope you get that particular scenario that I'm trying to tell you.
PAUL: Okay, now, generally, how this metric works in simple terms. Okay? Now, this metric actually generate hypothetical questions.
PAUL: Okay, so let's, let me tell you the working.
PAUL: Okay. So, how this particular… just like last time, we had taken an example of claims, so based on that only, we'll be doing it here, okay? So here, like, it will generate some type of hypothetical questions that the answer would be suitable for.
PAUL: Huh.
PAUL: Okay, the answer when I'm writing, it means that the generated, a response from the LLM.
PAUL: Generate the hypothetical questions that the answer, okay, would be suitable for fine. I will write it here.
PAUL: Okay? Now, based on the portion that we had last time that we have taken, what is the capital of France? Okay, now, if the answer was, like, the Eiffel Tower is beautiful. Okay. Now, based on that, okay, now, if you ask, the system will generate questions like, okay, where is the Eiffel Tower?
PAUL: Okay, now these type of questions, that can be generated, and these are totally hypothetical, guys. Okay? For now.
PAUL: So, now these questions, because whenever you are working with evaluation metrics, okay, you'll be making a lot of LLM calls, simply to check fact and to do multiple stuff. So, generally, this evaluation takes a lot of time, that's why. And you might get timeout error issues also, due to multiple LLM calls in one shot.
PAUL: Now, this is the first step, it means that from the main question, you will be creating some questions, and based on that, you will be asking. Now, the idea is to compare those generated questions with the original questions.
PAUL: Okay, fit?
PAUL: Duh.
PAUL: original questions.
PAUL: And now, how the compiling is done?
PAUL: At any point of time, if you compare question 1 with question 2, how it can be compared?
PAUL: Cheers, guys.
PAUL: Two sentences are there, how we will do the… Similarity or MMR?
PAUL: Okay.
PAUL: All right.
PAUL: embedding.
PAUL: Simply, the idea is that, okay, using embeddings, you will try to do the comparison of the generated question with the actual question, or the original question, in simple terms.
PAUL: Good.
PAUL: Now, the question comes, based on the answer that I'll be getting from Step 2. Okay, so where we are really looking for
PAUL: higher similarity.
PAUL: At the end of the day, the idea is that your generated question should be highly similar to your actual question.
PAUL: Then I can say that the answer is more relevant.
PAUL: Okay? If somehow… Lower similarity score is coming.
PAUL: It means that… less… relevant.
PAUL: Answer.
PAUL: high distance tool, nothing with respect to distance, with respect to, simply… I'm talking about similarity right now.
PAUL: Okay?
PAUL: So, the actual output that will come, so this is basically this particular step that you…
PAUL: Okay, so the idea is you generate hypothetical questions, you try to compare those with your original questions. Now, based on that, whatever the output that you will be getting, okay, if you are having a higher similarity, it means that more relevant, and if you are looking for a lower similarity, it means less relevant, in simple terms for now.
PAUL: Right. So, like, the same example, we can take it and we can, like, build, and we can do some type of calculations.
PAUL: Okay? Now, generally, here, what happens? So, if answer relevancy, okay, so your…
PAUL: Answer.
PAUL: relevancy. If I say that, if it is 1,
PAUL: Then what is the meaning, and if I say that it is zero, then what is the meaning?
PAUL: Can I say that 1 means that the answer directly to the address's question?
PAUL: Okay, it means that whatever the context you were looking for from your answer, everything was there. Pretty much a perfect answer in simple terms that I can say.
PAUL: Okay, so the answer directly, okay, to the address question, okay. Now, zero, if I'm talking about, it means that somewhere, okay, I can say it can be…
PAUL: A little bit.
PAUL: Okay, so…
PAUL: Of the track in simple terms. Of the track, I can say that, okay, completely off-topic in simple terms.
PAUL: Okay, and anything in between 0 and 1, you can think about partially off-topic, okay? So here…
PAUL: Okay, anything in gate between 0 to 1, we refer to as partially.
PAUL: off topic.
PAUL: It means that some type of additional information that has been added, okay? By then.
PAUL: 1 is equal to 100% relevant, directly relevant? Okay. No.
PAUL: Is underrated question should be equal to wrong answer, like, if the answer is 10 for France.
PAUL: Yes, then it will actually check the context, really, Mammoth. In your context, if somewhere it is written, the capital of France is Spain, okay, then it will be as a correct answer.
PAUL: Just because your external ground truth has been defined in such a way.
PAUL: Alright.
PAUL: Now, okay, so probably let's take that same NFL example, okay, just like last time we have taken it. Again, the same thing that we will try to do.
PAUL: Okay, so first of all, let's take an, user, okay, input.
PAUL: If you remember, like, see, the question, I will try to keep it same, okay? When was the
PAUL: First, okay, SB. So, remember, I'm talking about Super Bowl right now, okay? Now, simply, now the, response that comes. Okay, the response was big, if you remember, a lot of things were there, okay? Like, date, first of all, the date part was there.
PAUL: The… First… Super Bowl if I directly see.
PAUL: Just wait.
PAUL: the first… Okay? So, right now, I'm just writing in short form.
PAUL: was held on Jan 15, 1967.
PAUL: This is the actual response that I have. Now, from our, retrieve context, which is basically the RC, okay, now this sentence was generated. Now, if you remember, in our retrieve context, a lot of things can be there.
PAUL: Just wait. Even I forgot. The first AFL, NFL, okay.
PAUL: AFL, NFL… Okay, after that, you have that championship and other stuff.
PAUL: Then, pretty big one.
PAUL: And then 15 to Jan… 1967 in LA for now, directly that I'm right.
PAUL: Now, when you actually, see this, PTOP context.
PAUL: So, now, based on the response.
PAUL: If you look, am I getting the exact thing? Because, see, right now, my requirement was not, like, okay, what was the championship, okay, where, like, what was the location and other stuff. But actually, in the retrip context, we do have those type of information.
PAUL: Because I can say that, these all, that response that I have, somehow they refer to
PAUL: good relevancy.
PAUL: Because the actual content that I was looking, okay, I have that. I don't have, actually, more information. Okay, right now I can say that, yes, there is no noise also, for now.
PAUL: Later on, if I'm talking about some poor relevancy example.
PAUL: Okay, so I will just take the R2 as a response 2 for now.
PAUL: Okay? Now, based on that, okay, now, if I say that the…
PAUL: Super Bowl? Okay. And after that is the annual championship game of NFL.
PAUL: Okay.
PAUL: Now, see, here I got an information, but I feel that this is partial information. It means that from the retrib text, okay, I can see that this part got picked up, this is fine.
PAUL: part, I feel that, alright, some part is that it's missing. Okay, because the actual answer that I was looking for, that is totally missing, so somehow I can say that this is having much more poor relevancy.
PAUL: Okay.
PAUL: Now, in simple terms, see, right now, this is a simple condition of certain questions that you ask, simple, introgative sentences. Okay, like, if I ask, like, when or what.
PAUL: Right now, if you actually look for, okay.
PAUL: In this case, what happened? If I say with respect to… What?
PAUL: And when.
PAUL: Few basic questions.
PAUL: So, I can say that, yes, this is actually talking about what?
PAUL: The real context is actually, about this, I can say, the annual championship game of NFL. That particular context has been retained, so I can say that he is partially, factually correct.
PAUL: Okay, but again, exact information, which the portion asked, when was the first Super Bowl? But that is not coming in the response. So, when part I can say that, yes, this part is missing.
PAUL: Okay, so because of that, I will say that this will be having lower relevancy. Okay, so somewhere, let's take the score of… okay, because, see, guys, now I'm taking some hypothetical score, just to tell you, okay, like, probably, like, 0.35.
PAUL: Okay, it means that, okay, this is partially correct, so based on that, I'm giving a certain number to this one.
PAUL: I hope you get it.
PAUL: Yes?
PAUL: It means that that score will be, somewhere around 0 to 1. 0 means totally out of the context, 1 means a perfect, somewhere in between, it means that mixed.
PAUL: Okay, some part correct, some part missing, okay, some part might be incorrect, okay? Because actually, if you look-see, this particular information that I have, this is from your retrieved context.
PAUL: This is nothing the LLM data has halluc… can I say that the LLM has hallucinated?
PAUL: When you look into the answer.
PAUL: This is exactly from the retrieveText that I have.
PAUL: Okay, it means that… Enduring generation?
PAUL: Something wrong that is gone.
PAUL: part of the LLM.
PAUL: Because I know my retrieve context was exactly correct, but during the generation phase, somehow that particular context has been lost. So this can happen. Okay, so that's why I'm talking about this one, because right now, there is no hallucination. Okay, it means that though the information was there, but somehow you have missed it.
PAUL: Oof.
PAUL: Alright, now, based on the simple example, okay, so let's try to do a simple,
PAUL: Scores, okay, so if I take… our last question, I will take it for now.
PAUL: Yep.
PAUL: Like, okay, where is I filter? Let's take that one only for now.
PAUL: Just wait.
PAUL: Where is Eiffelta?
PAUL: Okay? Now, the first answer, if I'm talking about, the actual, response that you have is…
PAUL: What will be the… okay, so directly I will say ET, okay, located in Paris.
PAUL: Okay, let's add that, okay? Now, in the next step, when you are actually looking into what are the context that has been retrieved from the vector DB, okay, RC part.
PAUL: Okay, the idea is that you will be having multiple chunks. Okay, now from that chunks, if I'm talking about, okay.
PAUL: The one can be… let's take the…
PAUL: ET? Okay. It can be directly if located in Paris?
PAUL: Because of that, you are getting this particular answer.
PAUL: What can be other type of context?
PAUL: Can I say Paris?
PAUL: Here's the capital of France.
PAUL: Okay? Now, probably your third context can be… Duh?
PAUL: It was built or something around, like, in the year, I can say, like, 1889.
PAUL: Okay.
PAUL: Now, the fourth one that I have. Let's take something totally out of context.
PAUL: Okay? Tekpisa originated in Italy.
PAUL: Okay.
PAUL: Okay, so this part. Now, if I say that, okay, now, these are the retrieved contexts. So, in,
PAUL: Right now, if I'm talking about these type of content very specifically, okay? So right now, that particular relevance, if you feel that, which particular chunk is much more relevant?
PAUL: If I sip?
PAUL: HT. What is HT?
PAUL: One is much more relevant to you.
PAUL: Yeah, so always remember, it means that from the response, the… where is ifilter located, I can say that, okay, these many things were actually retrieved from the contest, but actually, I got this actual information, which was from the first tag.
PAUL: So, I can say that, yes, the answer is relevant, okay? Highly, highly relevant. It means that exactly what by what it is matching. The ET located in Paris, the ET is located in Paris. So, this is actually a 100% relevancy.
PAUL: Okay, now, if the response changes, okay, now, based on this, because whenever you are doing a similarities code, you will be looking into the top 4 chunks, and based on those 4 chunks, your response will be generated. So, always remember that, okay, the other chunks can also play some crucial role.
PAUL: Though…
PAUL: there can be some amount of information which is relevant, but really, some other information which is not relevant. So, all these cases that I will say that, it is not relevant.
PAUL: Okay? Because there is some amount of relevancy as well as some amount. Because this condition is totally out of context, this one.
PAUL: It really doesn't have any context here. But I can say the ET was built in 1889, okay, something related to ET, I can say that, okay, some amount of context, but really, like, where is Eiffel Tower? That is not coming.
PAUL: So, yes, the Eiffel Tower was probably in some other chunk. Because of that, that chunk might be selected, and your response in the LLM was manipulated. So, I hope everybody is getting that, why I brought this
PAUL: multiple rhetry contexts, because from… you will be getting multiple contexts. Now, out of those contexts, yes, there can be that, okay, from this particular context, the LLM is actually much more dominating. Okay, because of that, there can be some things with respect to your final answer. So, this is what refers in simple terms.
PAUL: Okay, answer relevancy. It means that how you are directly addressing the question.
PAUL: Perfect. Now, this part is done. Okay, now I will actually move to the next part with respect to… because I think we have discussed two metrics right now, and both the metrics are from
PAUL: The generator phase. One is the faithfulness, the other one is the relevancy. Okay, so both are from the generator phase, I can say. Let's take one something from, what is there? First one is CP, context precession, okay? This is from Retrieval.
PAUL: Alright, okay, let's take, then, context.
PAUL: Okay, for our context, precision, I need retryption. I think this particular example will work even here. Okay, so I will just do a little bit of revamping on the same part.
PAUL: Okay? Context.
PAUL: predicament.
PAUL: Okay. Little bit of theory is there, and this part is important, because it's 12.30. Do you guys, want to continue tomorrow? Because, again, if I start discussing, it will take 15 to 20 minutes, much more.
PAUL: How long is the class? Yes, 12.30 we can go through. Okay, so let's do it tomorrow, okay? Because this part only, then I will do the editing, okay? And this particular PDF, we will continue in the next class. I won't be changing the PDF, but I'll be sharing today's PDF.
PAUL: Alright, it's fine, it's loot in English, I can understand.
PAUL: Alright, so…
PAUL: Because with the practicals, see, again, LLM as a judge, see, tomorrow I want to complete LLM as a judge. If I cannot complete it, probably then I will skip that lecture, because from next week, I'll be starting with parcels, that way.
PAUL: Otherwise, tomorrow's class, I need to make it much more.
PAUL: Okay, because it's an additional topic, and I need to cover it. So that's why tomorrow's class might be extended.
PAUL: Today, I'm not extending, but tomorrow, for sure, it will be.
PAUL: Okay, because the notebooks I've shared already, I think that you can always go through that
PAUL: Content, the core content.
PAUL: Okay, alright.
PAUL: Now, I will start taking some questions, okay, because the core part is done, and anybody with respect to…
PAUL: Sir, a quick revision needed. File regarding what? You need the revision.
PAUL: Just only two topics we have done for that also, hmm?
PAUL: Okay, I will be sharing the PDF, don't worry, the notes will be done.
PAUL: Should it be comparing the generated answers with the… instead of the push… okay, okay, okay. If I'm talking about generated answers, no, Rishi, it will be questions. Just wait. Rishi, as Rishi is telling… let me start, sharing the iPad, okay?
PAUL: If I have made a mistake, I will just go through that.
PAUL: Mmm… no, I have written questions only, no.
PAUL: generated questions with your original questions. Okay, this part is correct. Asheep, please have a check.
PAUL: Alright.
PAUL: Okay, if it is not working, we'll be looking into that. Abhijay Trustee, then I will take Sanjay Shabu, then there is Deba, there is Digvijay. Okay, a few people I'm unmuted, okay, so let's start the discussion.
PAUL: Can you share the iPad doc, right now? Just give me then one minute, okay, let me upload it in Google Tribe. Okay, then only I will share. Just give me one minute, okay?
PAUL: This note says, like… Okay, I'm on this…
Sanjay Sagore: I will just write the notes for now, VDB, little bit of…
PAUL: Vector database that we discussed, and metrics.
PAUL: Good morning.
PAUL: Okay, my clicks here, ETRICS… A quick export, let me do a teardrop.
PAUL: Okay, just wait, I'm uploading into Google Drive, and from Google Drive, I will just share it with you.
PAUL: Google Pride, right?
PAUL: This is my drive.
PAUL: This is Ultimate Rag… Today's date is 29th November 2025, which is… Boom.
PAUL: 1990?
PAUL: Alright, I have the link with me now. So, I'll be sharing the link in the Notion.
PAUL: Shit…
PAUL: Alright, let me just share my screen and share it with you.
PAUL: This is green, the desktop 3, I think.
PAUL: Yeah, so here, with respect to motion…
PAUL: Okay, alright. Super Babbi, this is November 29th.
PAUL: Okay, so I've shared it, please have a look.
PAUL: Alright, so let's start our Q&A.
Abhijit Prusty: Hey, hi Paul, how good you.
Digvijay: iPhone?
PAUL: First, garbage go.
Abhijit Prusty: Paul, I have just a basic, under… just trying to understand. We have these, ragas which you mentioned, right? They're emulating on top of the output of the rag.
Abhijit Prusty: So what I was trying to understand is, like, we… for the RAG, right, we already use similarity search, and we found out the, like, this is the actual answer and all. Internally, how does this RAGAS, they make a connection saying, like, okay, your RAG output is correct or not.
Abhijit Prusty: They're using some scoring and all, but in… but overall, like, just for understanding how internally that evaluate what it does.
PAUL: Tomorrow, we'll be talking about that one.
Abhijit Prusty: Okay.
PAUL: And the second thing… One thing we discussed with respect to the practical. So, like, these things… don't ask practical questions now, because practically, when we'll be doing the implementation, we'll be looking into that, no?
Abhijit Prusty: Okay, okay, sure.
PAUL: Check the notebook that I have shared, try to execute it, you will get an overall idea, exactly. Because you have to create your own evaluation set.
Abhijit Prusty: Right.
PAUL: Okay, so that's why, like, once I show the practicals tomorrow, things will be much more clear.
Abhijit Prusty: And, Paul, one more question is, like, if you want to learn more about this LLM as it does, right, for the next class, what are the things we should go through, like, just for a preparation?
PAUL: Nothing you need. There is no such rocket science. These things are pretty much simple concept lines.
PAUL: Okay, check the notebook. The same thing that I have done, okay, that groundness, relevancy, these things, manually, that I'll be doing it through a prompt.
PAUL: Okay, check the notebook once. Sure, sure. Okay, you will get an idea.
Abhijit Prusty: Thanks, bud.
PAUL: Next, Sanjay.
Sanjay Sagore: Yes, sir, thankful. So, just, I want to…
Sanjay Sagore: I have one question, like, I'm on sub-project, like, my internal project only.
Sanjay Sagore: So, here I have the set of queries from Snowflake.
Sanjay Sagore: Based on.
PAUL: Set up queries from?
Sanjay Sagore: Snowflake, snowflake.
PAUL: a snowflake. Alright, fine.
Sanjay Sagore: Yeah, these are the long queries, so there are many, about 42 to 50 queries I have, but these are a long one.
Sanjay Sagore: And now, based on this, I want to just create a rake system.
Sanjay Sagore: Right now, I'm generating the report in Visual Assign. User can go to the application and can see the report.
Sanjay Sagore: Through the script.
Sanjay Sagore: Alright, so just want to prepare one,
Sanjay Sagore: reg system where user can input the, just, text or report name, and he can just, see the report.
Sanjay Sagore: So, just whether I have to embed the SQL queries, or do I need to prepare the metadata and then embed the queries also, or how, really, just one T or something.
PAUL: Totally say, I have to analyze your data and other stuff. Without seeing this stuff, if you have some type of POC that you can share, okay, like, through a notebook and other stuff, you can share it with me. Because I need some structure, some schema, how directly I can…
Sanjay Sagore: Okay…
PAUL: You are telling me everything in high level. I need to actually look into some stuff, at least
PAUL: Because then only I can give you an idea, at least, at this approach that you can take.
Sanjay Sagore: Okay, okay, can I send you mail, I think? That will be…
PAUL: Yes, drop me a meal.
Sanjay Sagore: Okay, good time.
PAUL: Whenever somebody's telling something like this, always
PAUL: come with a POC. Without a POC, it's very hard for me to analyze stuff.
Sanjay Sagore: If somehow the code knows… in that case, there is no data limit.
PAUL: You can just take a Google collab or your local notebook, take a partial amount with just few queries, okay, and based on that, what is your expectancy with respect to the solution? Okay, those things at least try to include, okay, and then let me…
Sanjay Sagore: Yeah, yes, I have the… those queries, just… I will send you the notebook also. Thanks for your time.
PAUL: All right, thank you.
Sanjay Sagore: Copy.
PAUL: Next, I think Devadik, Vijay, you guys can go ahead.
deba: Hi, hi, Paul, audible, right?
PAUL: Yeah, yeah, bottom.
deba: Okay, one question is, this is a real use case for my project. I recently got some opportunity. So, once the LLM is, used for the retrieval, maybe the answers are coming… coming out, right? The requirement…
PAUL: The LLM will be used for retrieval, first of all, tell me that.
deba: No, no, no, I mean, so the retrieval part, I mean, not the… In the retrieval part.
deba: When we are getting, for example, if you put K equals to 5, so 5 answers are coming, right? 5, yeah. So, I… if I have to generate, again, certain questions, like a chatbot, right? Then, how is the process, actually? So, do I need to embed the answers?
PAUL: No, no, wait, wait, wait, you want to generate questions based on your, chunks?
deba: Benner, based on the… answers we are getting in the, first, first part. Maybe, there is.
PAUL: First, what means, the answer from the LLM?
PAUL: Some did it.
PAUL: Okay, it means that the response that you are getting from there, you want to generate questions.
PAUL: In simple terms, if I say no, more questions in simple terms.
deba: Questions, correct, correct.
PAUL: Here's that part you can generate.
PAUL: Using another LLM, simply you can do that in addition.
deba: So, do I need to go with the same loop? Like, we have to retrieve the answers, and we have to embed.
PAUL: No, no, you… let's see. No, no, no, no. Why, again, the retrieval process? Directly, if you have the response from the LLM, and based on that, you want to generate. So, then why you will be looking into the retrieval?
PAUL: You can do a validation, very specifically that, okay, now this question is correct, or this question is addressing which retrip chunk.
PAUL: In that way, you can do your validation thing. But once the LLM has generated the response, you can ask another LLM, okay, based on this, try to generate 5 FAQs, okay, or something like that, if I talk about.
PAUL: Okay, now once that is generated, now that validation needs to be done, so where an embedding check or something like that, you will be doing manually.
deba: Okay, so that means another LLM has to be triggered to generate…
PAUL: game in a little more.
deba: To generate the question?
PAUL: It's not necessary. The idea is that another LLM instance retains it.
deba: Okay, okay, okay. So that's one question. Another question is, for example, the metadata management.
deba: So, if we are allowing many users to come in and to put the questions, right? So, so there could… there… okay, so how it happens, for example, ChatGPT-like system. So, there are many users coming and asking the questions. Is ChatGPT something like they are retrieving the questions and, they are doing their metadata management for the users.
deba: Or something like that, Chris?
deba: Amazing.
PAUL: Data Management, you have to do.
PAUL: internally, like, if you are building your system, ChatGPT is not a direct write system, neither it's, like, open source that they have any specific design. Okay, but any general-based systems, if I'm talking about, okay, yes, a proper metadata management that needs to be done from your side.
PAUL: Because at the end of the day, that is where the optimization is done.
deba: Okay.
PAUL: Okay, because without.
deba: I don't store that, right?
PAUL: Yes, yes, yes, in VectorDB, we'll be storing, no?
deba: Today we will be storing, yeah, okay.
deba: Okay.
deba: Got it. And one just question, actually, that you are using, maybe it's not relatively technical, it is like the notepad that you are using, right? Is that something we can also use for our,
deba: Clothing.
PAUL: ESG is a notability you can use.
PAUL: Okay, this is a notability? Yes, I need a notability.
deba: Okay, okay.
deba: Well, things are good.
PAUL: Next, Digvijan.
Digvijay: Yeah, hi, Paul. Can you please share us some interview questions on these topics of RAG? It'll be helpful. And scenario-based questions.
PAUL: Alright, because based on scenario, drop me a set of questions, and based on that, I will respond to you back.
PAUL: Okay, whatever that scenario and those questions that you have very specifically, okay, drop me a mail with the detailed information, and based on that, I will respond to you back, okay?
Digvijay: Oh, even if you have an interview set of questions, which we can… which will help me interview questions. Really, I don't have a set, because, see.
PAUL: It totally depends upon the GD.
PAUL: Okay, really, like, that set of questions changes, but I can create a message with you, but I don't feel that
PAUL: Again, at the end of the day, what matters is something like
PAUL: That particular project that you have previously worked on.
PAUL: Okay, few generic things I can share with you, but project-specific, nothing I can share. So, if you want, probably I can create a set and, like, the mail that you will be dropping, I'll be sharing that, okay?
Digvijay: Okay, blanking that.
PAUL: Alright, next, let's go with, Rajit Khanna, Madhasar Hakkeem, and I will take, Mamad MJ.
PAUL: Okay, people who are in the US, please let me know, okay? I will just try to take priority to the US guys.
PAUL: Okay.
PAUL: whoever is there in chat, you can let me know. Okay? Yes, I think they can… Rahul Parihar in… okay, Rahul Parihar, Rahul, you have raised your hand, okay. Rahul, done.
PAUL: Boomika, Boomika, alright, Bumica also, I have one more detail.
PAUL: Hi, Paul.
PAUL: Yes.
Rajat Khanna: Yeah, yes, so my question is not related to technical, it's related to applying on the industries. So, as we are on initial phase or applying these AI solutions in our companies.
Rajat Khanna: So, what, is the practical implementation? Like, after completing this course, we have a basic tool, intermediate understanding about the Gen AI. So, so while giving the interviews, and what, what roles that market are expecting?
PAUL: See, right now, the most basic… see, rules, exactly, I cannot say. Rules can be anything, you have to understand.
Rajat Khanna: Note on names, like, note on the names, like, what is market, means current Indian IT market will be expecting as a, AI.
PAUL: Indian IT market is much more about RAG rather than L&S, true to say. Correct, correct. It's pretty much about prompt engineering, little bit.
Rajat Khanna: That is…
PAUL: less technical, because really, in India, nobody has prompt engineers, but really, prompt engineering is a different task.
PAUL: Okay, but the AI guys do it. Okay, so, really. So, that's why I feel that Indian market side is much more towards building RAG and directly consuming existing LLMs which are available.
Rajat Khanna: Okay, so…
Rajat Khanna: My question comes in, as I'm a front-end UI guy, so by December, we are completing our application, and as an innovation part, so I suggested, like, while we have created this application, we will be creating an AI-driven model for this, like a RAG application, which will be showing the same set of information, just in a prompt format.
Rajat Khanna: So, might be January or February onwards, I'll be… I'll be working on those things.
Rajat Khanna: So, that is what my question was about, like, after completing that project. So, if I try to change the company and try to try my skills in the market, what is the particular focus my should be? So, as you answered, it will be RAG and prompt engineering. Is there anything else?
PAUL: There is no such a little bit about LLMs which I feel that
PAUL: It is required certain topics with respect to quantization. I feel it is important, because rather than using an entire model, how to quantize it and how to use it. Those are LLM stuff, not related to RAG.
Rajat Khanna: But I feel that, yes, that part is important.
Rajat Khanna: And also, like, while giving the interviews in the… our current IT market, so the persons who will be taking the interviews, like, will be like us, those who have just gained information one or two years back.
PAUL: really, like, I feel that it doesn't matter who is taking the interview, if you are really good into applications and research.
Rajat Khanna: Okay. The research papers that we'll be dealing with, okay, very specifically, if you're good in that.
PAUL: the actual core foundation, okay? So, you can have a really good and debatable internet.
PAUL: Indian market, really, like, the… I have seen in service-based organizations who take the interview.
PAUL: they might not be so much up-to-date. That's a major problem, okay? It means that you have to say that, okay, now this is the Peru, and this is the COM. Okay, it means that probably this is something, an existing stuff, but actually, like, this is a new paper, and based on this, yes, this implementation can be taken into account.
PAUL: So that thing, how to upgrade system is very important, because I feel that, actually, if you are into applications.
PAUL: People don't use the latest stuff. They will try to stick to something old, which is very stable.
Rajat Khanna: Okay, so actually upgrading systems, like.
PAUL: Nobody wants it.
PAUL: It's a simple idea in India, chalrah to chal den.
Rajat Khanna: Hmm.
PAUL: That's a step. Okay, so that's why it's not always about an active R&D team who is doing stuff and upgrading, so really it doesn't happen. Okay.
Rajat Khanna: So, as in, like, the main crux will be, like, we need to be good in implementing RAG and all these things, and also, whatever the RAG includes, and in theory part, we should be good in that theory. So, when, while giving the interviews, so if they…
Rajat Khanna: There will be a debate or questionnaire based on the theory, so we will be able to tackle this, though these are the old techniques, and these are the new ones that are more efficient,
Rajat Khanna: Only current research.
PAUL: Little bit, I feel that, what is the trend that is going on? You need to analyze that trend, the stuff that is coming. Little bit news you should have, like, you should subscribe to Alpha Signal. Okay, it's from where you get, actually, daily news. So, what is happening in this particular space?
PAUL: Okay, so I feel that that is important.
Rajat Khanna: Okay, yeah, thank you, thank you. Nit.
Bhoomika Nanjaraja: Hey, Paul.
PAUL: Okay, first, Bumika, go ahead.
PAUL: Yeah. Bumika, Mahmar, then Rahul.
Bhoomika Nanjaraja: Okay, so first of all, thank you so much for writing down all of those steps to explain the working of the different metrics, right? So, however, I'd like to know when you, when you said that you would be implementing it, tomorrow.
Bhoomika Nanjaraja: would you show us the implementation of each of those steps, and demonstrate how the results would look like? For example,
Bhoomika Nanjaraja: You know, creating the, those, you know, hypothetical questions, and comparing those questions using
Bhoomika Nanjaraja: The similarity. And all of that. Would you be showing us the step-by-step…
PAUL: Okay, I'll be taking the metrics through the framework, okay? Few things directly, even the metrics won't tell you.
PAUL: that this is generated, this is generated. Neither it is directly available in Dragas. That's through few things that can be debugged that I can show you, okay? Like, probably then again, through Jupyter Notebook, I cannot do debugging.
PAUL: Okay, probably I will be adding a few print statements with few examples to show you. But exactly the internal working of Raga's framework that I won't be showing you.
Bhoomika Nanjaraja: Yeah, how can we, like, you know, if, suppose, if we wanna, like…
PAUL: create a manual Python function, and I can share a notebook if you want to go through that.
Bhoomika Nanjaraja: Yes, Pris, that would be really helpful, or you can share some resources, you know.
PAUL: Because the thing that you are asking, okay, if you really look, know where you will be getting that.
PAUL: Because…
Bhoomika Nanjaraja: Yeah, I agree.
PAUL: your, requirement is very niche. Okay, it happens in pretty much low level, but in majorly all the frameworks implementation, just like in SQL, if I'm talking about. In SQLUN, it's pretty much function call, and through that, you understand. Okay, so here also, it will be pretty much function call.
PAUL: Okay, what I can do, I can take a single sample. Then again, if I take a single sample, then evaluation set is out of the context.
PAUL: So, that's why, like, directly, that is, manually, I'll be creating that, but that won't be part of that set.
PAUL: Okay?
Bhoomika Nanjaraja: Yeah, manually you would be creating it, I… so, would you…
PAUL: Everything will be manually, that's why.
PAUL: Because right now, whenever I'm working with, I need a data set, actually, to do multiple iterations of that. So if you ask me to do a single set validation, like a single example, I cannot do the actual validation. So that will be a manual implementation that I'll be showing there.
Bhoomika Nanjaraja: Okay.
Bhoomika Nanjaraja: So, and also, would you be, like, you know, like,
Bhoomika Nanjaraja: letting us know how to resolve these problems. For example, be it hallucination, or whenever noise is being generated, so…
PAUL: Right now, it's much more about the metrics, not solving. Like, see, if you are getting
PAUL: probably if you have some type of hallucination issues. Now, that's different to solve it. Right now, not in this particular topic. In other models, it will become.
Bhoomika Nanjaraja: Okay, you would cover it later on, that's fine.
PAUL: Right now, it's all about the metrics.
Bhoomika Nanjaraja: Okay.
Bhoomika Nanjaraja: So about the manual part, I did not get that 100%. Probably, I'll understand it once you implement it and show, or, you know…
PAUL: Because in most of the framework, it's direct, direct function call, okay, because a few things I have to do. See, the main problem that we do have is manual evaluation set variation.
PAUL: That is the main problem, okay? And that part, like, even I will be creating it manually by taking a sample document, okay, and then I have to actually use HuggingFit dataset, I have to create a evaluation-based format, then I have to pass it to Raga's.
PAUL: So, that's why. And all the six metrics, I'll be implementing it in one shot. Like, we can use only single one, I have no issues in that. We can comment always, and we can change it. I do… will be having a list of metrics, so you can simply comment it out and test it.
Bhoomika Nanjaraja: I agree, you would be doing it, but what would be the granularity of whatever you're gonna do is… because, like you told, what I'm.
PAUL: See, the granularity depends upon the framework. If the framework doesn't have any function or anything to expose that, you can't expect me to do that.
Bhoomika Nanjaraja: Yeah, I agree. But then, you talked about, creating hypothetical questions, and doing… Similarity.
PAUL: manually through Python that I have to show you, not through a framework.
PAUL: That's my impression. No, that is manual implementation. You won't understand, but I will tell you that, okay, these are the questions.
PAUL: That's true.
Bhoomika Nanjaraja: Okay, sure. But you would be doing that, right? Like.
PAUL: Really, I have not planned for that. Okay, as you're told, probably, I will add it.
Bhoomika Nanjaraja: Yes, please, if… that would be very helpful.
PAUL: That's the part, like, every part I… and probably if I try to cover this LLM judge.
PAUL: That I can't discuss.
PAUL: That's why, like, if I try to add one more topic, some other topic, that might be fine, but I would try to.
Bhoomika Nanjaraja: You could share a notebook, too, and, you know.
PAUL: By only sharing a notebook, see, it means that others might have the same requirement. Notebook, I already shared LLM with the email. You can always have a look into that. But again, at the end of the day, I feel that it is much more important.
PAUL: Alright, because at the end of the day, even if you are working with your own rag.
PAUL: Okay, and really, when you have 1 billion data set, you only be doing for every question what are the hypothetical questions that are getting generated. It is not possible.
Bhoomika Nanjaraja: Bye.
PAUL: There's something interesting.
Bhoomika Nanjaraja: Yeah, okay.
PAUL: But for one example, you can, like, by making a.
Bhoomika Nanjaraja: Yes, right. Just to understand, metric internal, working of those metrics, right? Like.
PAUL: I will check, see if it is in Ragas directly, because really the thing that you are asking, neither it is in DVL, neither it is in Ragas, I know. Okay, but, let me see, at framework level, what I can do.
PAUL: Interesting.
Bhoomika Nanjaraja: Sure, thank you so much.
PAUL: Alright.
PAUL: Yes, next, mommat or Rahul Pariah, anyone can vote.
Mohammad(MJ): Yes, hello, this is Muhammad. First of all, thank you for all the information provided to us and for your patience. So, I do have, actually a couple of questions.
Mohammad(MJ): One of the questions, maybe it's touching on the assignment you gave to us, which is I did finish it yesterday, but it's just a general question, and I understand how to resolve it, but I just want to check if it's practical. The question is, when you have a hybrid drag, and you do have multiple retrievers.
Mohammad(MJ): That, get you the information. But when you get the…
PAUL: See, like, you have… hybrid rag is different.
PAUL: Hybrid retriever is different.
Mohammad(MJ): So that's why, really, I want to understand what's the exact thing that you were telling me.
Mohammad(MJ): So, basically, on the assignment, like, we are having multiple retrievers, right?
PAUL: Hmm.
Mohammad(MJ): So, basically, if it's not available in local, it's gonna go try to look on a different retriever, and could be external, or could be something else, so…
Mohammad(MJ): So you end up with multiple retriever, but the point I'm trying to make sure in here, as I was going over all the sheets, there is some code that we have. It tells us the source from where the information, or which retriever got you the information, basically to determine the source.
Mohammad(MJ): From practical perspective.
Mohammad(MJ): Which is the answer that we have is, you have to call each retriever to invoke it, to find out the source. If you don't find it in one retriever, you're gonna call the other retriever. But is that practical?
Mohammad(MJ): Really? To find out the source?
PAUL: I really see, we'll be setting a priority. It means that the first one, most of the times, you'll be getting the answer from.
PAUL: Okay, and the other external retrievers, for example, if I take Tablei, that is your final, it means that everything has failed, and you have nothing to provide.
PAUL: Then you'll… then only your final call will be using, like, XR or through TALI. That is the idea. Your main vector DB retriever will fail, then only you will move to the next year.
Mohammad(MJ): Okay.
Mohammad(MJ): So, in the chain we have today, that I know that some of the code you provided, that basically what it does, it starts calling each of the retrievers, and it does a join of all the documents' content. But technically, what's supposed to happen is, it's gonna do the first call.
Mohammad(MJ): If there is no response, based on that, you start calling the other, moving to the next steps.
PAUL: Yes, so generally, like, if I show you the assignment, I think here I've given… so based on this particular, code structure that I've given. Okay, it's a simple, the idea was that, okay, so here you can see slash nin slash join context, okay.
PAUL: Now, if local docs… local docs at this particular retriever, okay, if you are getting this from this information, if it's good.
Mohammad(MJ): Okay, otherwise directly.
PAUL: It will go to the, like, Wikidocs in simple terms. Okay, so the idea is always to invoke the first one, which will be your local one. If the local fell, then only you will move to something which is an external label right here, which is the Wikipedia one.
Mohammad(MJ): Yes, definitely. And basically.
Mohammad(MJ): creating some helper method and some utility to determine, really, which one, then based on that, you determine which is the one you call for invoke, to find out the source. Sure. I get that, yeah, definitely, like, I understand this code, and I… I know how it works. All right, thank you, Paul. This is for the first question.
Mohammad(MJ): The second one, actually, should be yes-no answer. So, I do have a book, it's talking about how to build
Mohammad(MJ): LLM from scratch, it's from code perspective, and start touching very deep in the transformer. Is it really worth going…
PAUL: I think building an LLM from scratch is written by Savasla and Roshka only, no?
Mohammad(MJ): Yes.
PAUL: That's the one. Yeah, yeah, yeah, I know. It's a great one.
PAUL: The book is good. Okay.
Mohammad(MJ): Okay, yeah, definitely then. Then that… I get the answer. It's good to go over it then.
Mohammad(MJ): Alright, I think that covered my questions. Thank you very much, Paul.
PAUL: Alright.
Rahul Parihar: Rings.
PAUL: Next, Rahul.
Rahul Parihar: Yep.
Rahul Parihar: Thanks, Paul, for patiently explaining,
Rahul Parihar: I'm taking time, you know, to explain the core concept of context metrics and answer metrics. So I have, 4 relevant questions, and I can email them also to you.
Rahul Parihar: The first is the context recall versus chunking. So, does…
PAUL: the.
Rahul Parihar: How does the changing…
PAUL: Context recall versus chunking. Basically, context recall is applied on top of your charts, which are available.
Rahul Parihar: Versus chunking, so I'm talking about versus chunking. So, does… does the change in the chunking size from 256 versus…
Rahul Parihar: 512 token impacts the context recall, you know?
PAUL: Correct.
Rahul Parihar: Does it mean that the smaller chunk can lead to missing information?
PAUL: Generally, like, for making your search more efficient, smaller chunks are better.
PAUL: But again, yes, I can say that if your chunks are smaller, there can be a problem where some amount of context is lost.
Rahul Parihar: Fuck you.
PAUL: But for efficient search, smaller chunks is required. So generally, that's why, like, what is the chunk size if, for example, like, 250, I feel that it's really small, so I always prefer something starting from at least 500, because I feel that 500 is somewhere around a good number.
PAUL: And the max that I can go is till 2000, with my experiments, through multiple, like I can say, A-B testing that I can do for different configurations.
Rahul Parihar: Got it.
Rahul Parihar: The second one is the ground-tooth creation, okay? So…
Rahul Parihar: there is something, called as generating a golden data set, right? If I have a ground tooth necessary to be accurately called as a context-free call.
Rahul Parihar: Do we need a human annotation or any synthetic data generation to be used, you know, in this mechanism?
PAUL: That mechanism you don't have… you have… will you be explaining that?
Rahul Parihar: See, creating datasets, that is different. Really, like, human annotators are required. Your subject matter expert, whoever is there, based on that particular use case.
PAUL: Okay, really. But, the idea is that, okay, so using my current.
PAUL: I can say, retrieve context, whatever the way that I'll be building. I will be creating a set.
PAUL: Okay, now, really, that golden rule that I… you were telling, okay, so the idea is because I will be building it from my initial set, it means that whatever the data set I will be having, a part of that I'll be taking it, and I'll be using it for evaluation.
PAUL: Okay, but I'll be taking the retrieve context as well as the responses from the LLM to do the evaluation.
PAUL: Okay, so, but it will be a subset of our main dataset. But, I…
Rahul Parihar: Oops.
PAUL: that actually in production, when you are working, you need, yeah, a little bit of that human in the loop, okay? So, yes, it means that it comes for at least a verification. It means that
PAUL: Yeah, for example, see, really, it totally depends upon your system. If you feel that in your use cases, there are millions which are coming, it is not possible even for human annotators.
PAUL: Okay, so in that case, because it might take a very, very long time, then you need to take some other action.
PAUL: Probably evaluating it through, probably a jury of LLMs. Okay, so in that way, we can do… it's not only about a single LLM, the idea is to use multiple LLMs and build the jury and do an evaluation.
PAUL: So, I have a feedback.
Rahul Parihar: I have a feedback loop mechanism where human interaction is important to track down that metadata, what user is responding.
Rahul Parihar: And the golden dataset gets updated based on the human annotations that are sent to the system.
Rahul Parihar: And it comes in a very large volume, and it's difficult to create that observability, or create that… dressing.
Rahul Parihar: To actually see what is the ground truth creation that user is trying us to do.
Rahul Parihar: That's a problem.
PAUL: I got your point. If it's a scale array, you can use multiple LLMs and other way to do an evaluation, because there is no other mechanism.
PAUL: Because I can say that you can always have a check that with this response from these 5 LLMs, and then you can actually have a voting.
PAUL: As simple as that.
PAUL: out of those boots, you can actually take it, okay. Finally, see, the idea is that at least that out of this very specific, or if you can use 7, 9, take an odd number, try to do it, but you should have a case, because there has to be some cases, probably I can say that out of 1 lakh, I can say that, okay, probably
PAUL: 80,000 were handled by your LEM, but at least there will be some cases, 10 to 15,000, that needs to be manually handled.
PAUL: Because everywhere there is an edge case.
Rahul Parihar: With edge cases, like, you will be making a system.
PAUL: Much more robust. That's why that human annotators will come. Like, at least somebody will be doing some type of evaluation where all those things have failed.
Rahul Parihar: Yeah, in my re-ranking process, we are sacrificing the context precision by including too many top K results, you know, just to boost the recall, you know.
Rahul Parihar: Factor. So, how to handle that?
Rahul Parihar: Like, trade-off… of precision trade-offs, you know?
PAUL: This is now to… this is a simple trade-off. Based on your use case, you'll be selecting. Generally, I prefer always going with a high recall, as compared to going with high precision.
PAUL: The… at the end of the day, what happens with the ground truth, that matters to me much more to me.
Rahul Parihar: Okay, okay.
Rahul Parihar: And how does the low precision,
Rahul Parihar: Correlates with halination rate in the… in the final generation.
Rahul Parihar: For the night…
PAUL: load.
Rahul Parihar: low precision.
PAUL: Okay.
Rahul Parihar: Correlates with hallucination rate in the final generation.
PAUL: It will correlate, no, because at the end of the day, the response that will be coming, it will be having some type of noise.
PAUL: With some type of virtual, factual info.
PAUL: So, there will be a correlation, if you are going with, like, lower precision at any point of time. Okay, I can say that the noise level, based on the LLM response, it will be towards the higher side.
Rahul Parihar: But how do you relate with the hallucination rate if you want to capture…
PAUL: Generally, like, the top… see, like, you were very specific to that, I got your point. Now, generally, I prefer higher recalls much more as compared to going always with higher precision. The idea is to always check your ground truths better.
PAUL: So I feel that recall, in every system that you are building, it should be much more about recall, rather than precision. I… because based on machine learning, everywhere, there's a golden rule that we have learned, okay? Now, with respect to lower precision.
PAUL: I can say that, yes, there can be hallucinations. Because of that, the noise level that gets introduced into the responses, it can be towards the higher side. But at least I can say that it will be always partial to your GT. So, directly, if you try to… direct correlation, if you ask me.
PAUL: Okay.
PAUL: with precision.
PAUL: And directly, what's the other metric that you told?
Rahul Parihar: The context predication versus hallucination rates.
PAUL: meter.
PAUL: Hallucination rates, when you are talking about.
Rahul Parihar: It means what?
PAUL: See, evaluation and race, if you are talking about, it means that the low faithfulness, or low ground, it's the simple terms, if I'm talking about. If you are trying to do a correlation directly with that, I will say that
PAUL: It won't be completely correlated. Can't.
Rahul Parihar: It will be highly correlated.
PAUL: No, no, it won't be highly correlated, I cannot say. So just think about if you… if your system is having a high recall, how can you say that, it will be having, like, high hallucinations?
PAUL: I don't think it can be fed.
Rahul Parihar: Yeah, that's… that's where… that's the point that I was not sure about, but, you know…
PAUL: At the end of the day, if your recall is high, I know that you are sticking much towards your GTs. And if you are sticking much towards your GTs, I can say that you'll be having lower ammunition, but I cannot really say that I'll be having higher ammunition.
Rahul Parihar: Okay.
Rahul Parihar: Some… another answer matrix, you know, like faithfulness, calculation. How do we distinguish between
Rahul Parihar: An answer that is factually true in the real world.
Rahul Parihar: Versus… One which is strictly grounded to the retrieve content, and that's coming as a big problem
Rahul Parihar: for any implementation that I'm… predominantly using it. Like, factual, true, in the real world versus the.
PAUL: CCC, factual, one is the GT, which is in your, like, retrieve context, okay? What is the other thing?
Rahul Parihar: Another one is the grounded, in the retrieve content, like, how you took an example of…
Rahul Parihar: say, what is the capital of Paris, right?
Rahul Parihar: So, you know the factual, true, in the real-world situation, what is the answer?
Rahul Parihar: But you are stricking, one that you are stricking with the grounded in the retrieve content. Whatever is retrieve, you're trying to capture that, but you're not relating it with the real world.
Rahul Parihar: factual,
PAUL: Yes.
Rahul Parihar: True real-world scenario, right?
PAUL: when you'll be doing that, again, you don't have the access to anything. It's all about the embedding comparison.
Rahul Parihar: Okay.
PAUL: Because, see, at the end of the day, during retrieval, do you think that with respect to the search, you can change your search method from similarity to MMR? You can do this, but really, at the end of the day, it's about the numbers.
PAUL: I cannot really say that, okay, probably this… the most common problem I do is the keywords. Probably I've written Paris.
Rahul Parihar: Yeah.
PAUL: Okay, that Paris can be in 100 charts.
PAUL: Okay, now out of that 100, really, now the question comes with Paris, what is the other context that is playing the crucial role?
PAUL: This is a major problem that we do face in that. So, probably through ranking, through a certain extent, we can handle it, but again, I feel that that is where noise comes into the picture. That's why…
PAUL: We specifically take that noise sensitivity metric, okay, and we try to calculate that.
Rahul Parihar: So, for tomorrow's lecture, I'm just kind of focused on the automation part of faithfulness scoring using LLM as a judge, right?
PAUL: No, no, no, no, LLM, as a judge, is a different notebook. Please, I will look at least.
PAUL: Tomorrow, see, tomorrow's implementation, you guys can execute it today also, if you have that. Okay, so if I show you, see, two notebooks are there, simple, one is RAG evaluation with RAGAS and RAG evaluation with LLM judge. Okay, now this one, if you will go through, okay, a simple RAG, I don't know, the notebook is very big.
PAUL: Okay, so majorly, if I talk about… this is a custom document that I have built. Okay, now setting up the rack, the idea is that till this point, you guys know everything. 3.7. So, this part I'll be doing later on, I'll be setting up directly Raga's. Okay.
PAUL: Now, these are basically the text cases with ground truth that I'll be manually creating. Now, this information that I'll be actually passing it as an evaluation data. So, through evaluation data, I will try to create a sample set. You can see questions, ground truth answers, rack-generated answers, retryptions.
PAUL: This is actually my evaluation set, how it will look like.
PAUL: Okay. Then, finally, like, once I have that, I will be converting into a supported RAGAS format through Hugging Face dataset, and then I will be directly passing it. Okay, so, for example…
PAUL: Okay, now this is the part where you have to do, and… because even when you are working with Ragas, you need to set up your LLM and embedding model. Okay, so generally, that is the default LLM that you can use. So for that, like, I will be using Chat, OpenAI, or some type of embeddings. And finally, I'll be just making a final call done.
PAUL: Okay, it means that this…
Rahul Parihar: What my… my question was… what I'm… I looked at this particular spreadsheet, this particular notebook, but I… what I'm looking for is the flag, you know, like the scoring that is using to flag when the model used the training data instead of the retrieved content.
Rahul Parihar: That is the part that I'm not able to see it in this.
PAUL: Flagging… see here, flagging I am not doing anywhere.
Rahul Parihar: Why? That's my question. Otherwise, how will you… how will we know that the Fitfulness core
Rahul Parihar: doing by the LLM as a judge is flagged properly. I know it's a question for tomorrow.
PAUL: I'm not using LLM as a judge here.
Rahul Parihar: Oh, okay.
PAUL: I'm using Radhaus. Okay, see, tomorrow. Because, see, your requirement is pretty much niche according to your use case. Okay, so that's why, like, you can let me know things in detail, because I feel that your requirement is pretty niche. It's not, like, a simple requirement that you have.
Rahul Parihar: Yeah, dude, I know.
PAUL: Flagging, because if I want to flag something, again, I have to use an observability tool, and through that.
PAUL: Through multiple examples, okay, now what will be the flagging criteria? Very specifically, like, through which metric that I want to pick up that one.
PAUL: Yeah, so that's why. Because, see, at the end of the day, if you look here, I have created a data frame. Okay, in that data frame, I have taken that metrics, and I have shown that, but again, like, tomorrow I'll be talking about that one.
Rahul Parihar: Yeah, in real-world scenario, we will be flag… we will flag the model used based on the training data, right, instead of the retrieve content.
Rahul Parihar: That's what is the principle that I've been using. Is it wrong?
PAUL: Training data means what? At the end of the day, training data, when you are referring it, means that the training is coming through your external docs only, no?
Rahul Parihar: Correct.
Rahul Parihar: But don't… yeah.
PAUL: So, training means at the end of the day, you are using some external docs. It means that if you retrieved whatever the document that you have passed, those things are in your vector TV. Okay, so that becomes your training data. Now.
PAUL: with respect to your inference data, it means that in real time, when somebody is asking some type of query, that becomes your main, I can say, your real-time inference questions.
Rahul Parihar: Okay.
Rahul Parihar: I'll be emailing you some of the specific questions and use cases that I'm trying to solve, maybe, with the codebase example, for sure, you know.
PAUL: That's why, like, your requirements is let me know.
Rahul Parihar: Critical, like, evaluation process is the most critical.
PAUL: Venuition is…
PAUL: much more complex. That part, really, like, in production, what I do, that I cannot really teach, then more than everybody will.
PAUL: Because for evaluation, it might take only, like, more than 2 months.
Rahul Parihar: Because it's an incremental system.
PAUL: Day one, there is no solution.
PAUL: I have to do weekly that stuff.
PAUL: Okay, so that's why.
PAUL: Alright, I got your point, Rahul. Okay, so let me know much more in details, and based on that, I will connect it to.
Rahul Parihar: Yep, sure. Thank you.
PAUL: Alright, so Mutastar Hakim, we are next, then Kiran Ratho, then we have Naga, MS, okay? So, yes, 4 people I have done. Yes, please let me know.
PAUL: Motasar?
PAUL: Okay, Muddhasar is telling, I will have to drop, we'll take up, today's queries tomorrow. Alright, fine.
PAUL: Then I think next, Karen.
Kiran Rathod: Paul, I am facing issue when, connecting with VV8, right? So the Docker, I have in… the Docker is installed in my local, but for some reason, the command that we're using, that's not working for me.
PAUL: It does not, it's a Docker-related issue. Okay, now I have added your panelists, share your screen and show me.
PAUL: Next, Emmet.
PAUL: MSMS…
MS: Yeah, hi, hi, can you hear me?
PAUL: Yes.
MS: Okay, so my question was a little more fundamental. So suppose, like, the example that you are taking, where is the capital of Paris? Sorry, where is the capital of France? Suppose the response that we get is that the Paris is the capital of France, and Africa is in Paris.
MS: Something like this. So then, how do you, give a certain score to this response? Because all these metrics that we have discussed so far in the class are subjective metrics, so how do you objectively give a score for those metrics?
PAUL: Now, the question that you have asked is neither in any framework, giving objective… But heh.
PAUL: Because directly we're telling that Because human annotators, again, like, directly there is no debt.
PAUL: Any framework, I don't think directly you can do that.
MS: Okay.
PAUL: Everything is a subject.
PAUL: At the end of the day, subjective metrics are there.
MS: Okay, okay, so that's my understanding as well, that you can't objectively quantify such answers, right? If something gets appended at the start or at the end of the correct answer, so then it can't be objectively quantified. Yeah, that was me.
PAUL: moderate Thomas.
PAUL: Okay, Hamid, I think… Yeah, yeah, hello. Can you hear me? Yes, Naga, yes, Tel.
Naga: Yeah, I'm going to share my screen.
PAUL: I lost you. Arth.
Naga: Can you hear me?
PAUL: Yes, I can hear you.
Naga: Okay, I want to share the screen.
Kiran Rathod: Yeah, I was sharing my screen for a Docker issue where I'm not able to install the VV8, right?
PAUL: Yeah, 10.
Kiran Rathod: When I use this command.
PAUL: What if they're telling me?
Kiran Rathod: It says Vivate is not identified, yeah, no module named Vivate.
PAUL: Then show me that a particular model is there or not.
PAUL: do a playlist and check. These are… see, don't tell me that module not found error. This is a generic Python.
PAUL: So show me your tip list and tell me that that is their own.
Kiran Rathod: It's available.
PAUL: This is a container, where is the package?
Naga: That's, that's my screen, maybe I didn't… you're seeing my screen.
PAUL: Okay, yours, now I am confused. Yeah, show me pick list, abbreviate.
PAUL: Viviate client, it's not, Viviate, I think it's Viviate-client, and the other packages,
PAUL: Check that, we'll be outlined both the packages soon.
PAUL: Langchen-Uviate one package was there. The other package was… please open the notebook. First of all, open the notebook.
PAUL: Open the notebook.
PAUL: Go at the top.
PAUL: At the top. Quickly scroll at the top.
PAUL: Scroll down, installation and Setup.
PAUL: These two packages are there in your system?
Kiran Rathod: No, let me just install it, and I'll try to connect.
Kiran Rathod: Stop my screen chat.
PAUL: Okay, next, Naga.
Naga: Oh, God.
Naga: You can see my screen?
PAUL: Yes.
Naga: booking.
Naga: So, I… I instantiated the VWIT in the Docker here, and it's running.
Naga: When I go to the… this, when I go to… Yeah, this,
Naga: In the… in this cell, yeah, it is saying that…
PAUL: That is a resource warning, nothing to worry about. Proceed ahead.
Naga: Yeah, so let's verify the Ollama is… okay, so I think this local store, it connected to the VWAT, created the vector store.
Naga: But then there's some error is coming, right? 4, not 4. It's okay, this one?
PAUL: telling model limbic test, try to connect with your ulama. If there is an issue with our ULAMA, then you will face this problem.
Naga: But Olama is running, like, Olama is running, and I was able to use it.
PAUL: So where is this? It's simply telling Nomic embed test not found. It means that that particular model, it's telling that it is not available, so probably with your ROLAMA, there can be some type of connection issue.
PAUL: Amit?
Naga: Can you hear me? Can you hear me?
PAUL: Give me if I can.
Amit Jain: fish. Okay.
Amit Jain: So Paul, I just have… see, I mean, right now we are discussing very, let's say, simpler cases wherein there are very clear question and answers, right? But in… so when we deploy these kind of RAG systems in… in enterprise production.
Amit Jain: the user queries we can't predict, right? So they can type in longer queries as well.
PAUL: Only a single word also be printed.
PAUL: So, my question is, yeah, so my question is.
Amit Jain: Typically, when the query is put in, do we also have a provision wherein we can… to retrieve… because I think the retrieval is the most critical step in RAG.
Amit Jain: So, is there a provision wherein we also break the incoming query into multiple parts, and then…
PAUL: That is an advanced topics, query decomposition. After Module 7, it will…
Amit Jain: Okay, and the other question is that?
Amit Jain: How do we, fine-tune that, you know, while you want your answers to stick to the documents.
Amit Jain: You have, or your database.
Amit Jain: But at the same time, you still want to leverage the knowledge of LLM itself.
Amit Jain: Then how do you kind of fine-tune and create that balance? Like.
PAUL: It's generally say, fine-tuning.
Amit Jain: No, not fine-tuning the LLM, I'm just saying that, creating that balance between how much, you want to use the capability of the LLM, or you are simply using LLM only for, kind of, rephrasing the retrieved context and just generating an answer, not adding any value from its own knowledge base.
PAUL: Generally, through retrieved scores, only we do retrie ranking, fusion, other things are there. Like, sparse vectors will also come into the picture.
PAUL: Hybrid system is there. Multiple ways, because right now, this is the bare minimum.
PAUL: Now, this retrieval technique, we will keep on improving, going forward in other models. Then you will understand.
Amit Jain: Huh, because, like, for example, as a… let's say I'm in a finance and accounting, I'm building a…
Amit Jain: database, or a RAG system, and a user might ask something very specific to our company's knowledge base, and in addition, may ask a question which is, let's say.
Amit Jain: a very generic one, which he could have gotten on ChatGPT as well, but then I want that person to stick to only my internal chatbot and not go to any other external system, so the MyRack chatbot should be able to be flexible enough that if it doesn't retrieve… if it doesn't have any solid knowledge within the knowledge base of the company, then it can still go to ChatGPT and retrieve the answer from there.
PAUL: Okay, like, yes, like, see, that is your final, see, at the end of the day, if your retrieval fails, okay, at any point of time. Now, see, the question that you are asking, it can be that the answer he was looking for, the LLM might already…
PAUL: In that case, a separate tool call is not required. If the LLM totally doesn't know, and neither your retriever is capable of doing that, okay, then finally you'll be making a final tool call to some external API, like ChatGPT or something like that.
Amit Jain: Hmm.
Amit Jain: Okay. So it kind of then becomes more of an agentic rag system, right?
PAUL: Yes. Like, if this fails in this, it's pretty much simple if-and-else case scenario based on some threshold that will be turning, like, setting up.
Amit Jain: Hmm. Okay, thank you. That was my question.
Naga: I solved that problem.
Naga: Paul, what one other problem is coming.
Naga: This…
Naga: Olama, I imported here, separately, and it says it is working. It sounds like it is working, something done.
Naga: But then I invoke, it's saying some deprecated warning…
PAUL: Warning, it's not an error, it's just a simple warning.
Naga: Okay.
Naga: So, disowned things.
Naga: Yeah, it is working that one. Yeah, I think this is done. Then, tell me about RAG.
Naga: Basic, similar to search, yeah, it is able to pull the information.
Naga: And, search with the metadata filter.
Naga: Yeah, I think it's been true.
Naga: The multiple and the logic conditions.
Naga: For the rent.
Naga: Feels some belly… Yeah, here, here's the error coming.
Naga: Why the error coming here?
PAUL: This is permission error. It means that somewhere… There is permission issue.
Naga: This is a permission denied.
Naga: Where it's saying permission denied? I don't see that.
PAUL: See, OS error, it's telling me.
PAUL: It's already locked.
PAUL: Yes, permission error is telling you the error, only the first line is telling permission error.
Naga: Farm machine, acha, sorry.
PAUL: That's fine.
PAUL: It's a waste level. See, try to restart or something like that, okay, try to reinitialize all your calls, because in a single notebook, you are making multiple calls, so sometimes that happens.
Naga: Restart the kernel, you think so?
PAUL: Yes, probably restarting the kernel. Don't execute all the cells, very specifically look and check the imports, specific where it was scaling, and then try to only execute that part.
Naga: Okay.
PAUL: Well, ski run.
Kiran Rathod: Now I'm getting issue with embedding. Vivate error, yeah.
PAUL: Name ending… embedding is not defined. So, what is the meaning of embedding is not defined. It means that you have not executed some cell where embedding has been defined at the top, probably with respect to Olama.
PAUL: Go ahead.
Naga: Yeah, you have to start the Ulama, then we run.
Kiran Rathod: Olama is running here, in the background.
PAUL: No, no, no, no, no, the sale you have to execute. No, that embedding was…
Kiran Rathod: The cell has been defined. Executed. I have executed all the cells prior to this.
PAUL: No, no, it's not required. Quadrant part, totally, you can skip. Right now, you are executing the weird part. Go at the top, top, top, top, top, top, top.
PAUL: scroll slowly, slowly. In the initial cells only, embedding, was defined. Slowly, slowly, yeah. Go down, down, down, down, down, down, down, down, down, down.
PAUL: Yes.
PAUL: this line.
Kiran Rathod: was executed.
Kiran Rathod: Okay, let me start reading now.
PAUL: Yes, because generally the green mark comes. Whole am I embedding is not, defined. First, do the import, then run it.
PAUL: Import, import, import.
PAUL: Import section, first run it.
PAUL: Yes, that was the import section.
Kiran Rathod: Okay, next, I'll just try to complete this.
PAUL: Alright, fine.
PAUL: Alright.
PAUL: I think no more questions for today. Lakshmi is there. Lakshmi, you have raised, Lakshmi?
Lakshmi: Hey, I'm getting issue with this long chain quadrant. I see the package is installed.
Lakshmi: I don't know, I have been trying for the last 30 minutes, so…
PAUL: Oh, great.
Lakshmi: practice and stuff, so… somewhere. It should be, I need some silly problem.
Lakshmi: Canadian Rescue Mission Ball.
PAUL: Start sharing, now I can't see.
Lakshmi: Okay, yeah, should be good, no.
Lakshmi: Well, consider…
PAUL: Media.
Lakshmi: Okay, so here… I have… I have all these packages already, so these two packages are already in there.
PAUL: Show me, show me.
Lakshmi: Okay, so…
Kiran Rathod: Paul, that's working, yeah, thank you.
Kiran Rathod: Alright. Thanks.
Lakshmi: So this is long chain quadrant, see here, long chain quadrant is there.
Lakshmi: And grab them blank.
Lakshmi: 1, 3, 2… Ship content client is also there.
PAUL: Alright.
Lakshmi: So, yeah, I will talk about this one later, but, if I just go and run this guy.
PAUL: disease…
Lakshmi: having a problem.
Lakshmi: I have restarted already the kernel.
Lakshmi: And it's the virtual environment which I have been using it.
PAUL: Okay, just write to… No, no.
PAUL: Open the Python shell and try to write that command from lengthen underscore quadrant, import, quadrant.
PAUL: Open the Python shell, copy-paste this command, and let's see.
Lakshmi: No.
Lakshmi: I tried… it's not showing up here.
PAUL: See, here it's telling it's not working.
Lakshmi: Right, so… what am I missing, I don't know.
PAUL: to uninstall and reinstall the package. Something happens.
Lakshmi: Vegas, okay.
PAUL: It happens. That's the only thing that you can do, because if it works here, then only it will work there. If it doesn't work here, you'll be having the problem.
Lakshmi: Okay, I'll do that.
PAUL: Perfect.
PAUL: Alright guys, so I think then I could conclude the session, okay?
Naga: One second, only one minute, both.
PAUL: Okay, Naga, then you share.
Naga: Number 11.
PAUL: Quickly, sir.
Naga: Boom.
Naga: So, I loaded the Langston document, this one, and install this embedding now.
Naga: Llama is running, okay. Then…
Naga: Shouldn't rolled up a munch.
Naga: quadrant.
Naga: No.
Naga: And then, no, my… okay.
Naga: Oh, my God, it didn't… Every time I would install this, I don't know what is the problem?
Naga: Updated version of the class.
PAUL: There is no issue proceeded.
Naga: No organization.
PAUL: To get confused with warnings and errors.
Naga: Okay, deprecated warning against also still okay, I think.
Naga: And, tell me about RAL.
Naga: Okay, similarity search, okay, metadata filter.
Naga: doing multiple condition.
Naga: Quadrant with local persistence. Yes, this is the error I was getting. Let's see, now it's fixed. Quadrant data, thank you.
Naga: Yeah, now the quadrant also got added.
Naga: Quadrant method… That's window.
Naga: Results with this course… Yeah, that's it, I think, yeah, that's it I got, you know.
PAUL: Alright, fine.
PAUL: All right, guys, so let's conclude for, today, okay? And tomorrow, we'll be continuing with our discussion.
PAUL: Bye, everyone.